sem_1 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'FUNCTIONAL ENGLISH',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'It was raining yesterday, so we __________ out.',
                        'options': ['did not go', 'did not went', 'would not go', 'would not gone'],
                        'answer': 'did not go'
            },
            {
                'question': ' I __________ what was happening.',
                'options': ['couldn’t understood', 'couldn’t understand', 'was not able to understood', 'would not able to understand'],
                'answer': 'couldn’t understand'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If you work hard, you __________ good marks.',
                'options': ['would get', 'would got', 'will get', 'will got'],
                'answer': 'will get'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If you __________ hard, you would not have failed in the exam.',
                'options': ['have work', 'have worked', 'had work', 'had worked'],
                'answer': 'had worked'
            },

            {
                'question': 'They will not come here, __________?',
                'options': ['won’t they', 'won’t them', 'will they', 'will them'],
                'answer': 'will they'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The newly installed application sounds very __________.',
                'options': ['interest', 'interested', 'interestingly', 'interesting'],
                'answer': 'interesting'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Our team played __________.',
                'options': ['bad', 'badly', 'good', 'well done'],
                'answer': 'badly'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Fatima is not at home at the moment, She __________ work.',
                'options': ['is at', 'is on', 'was at', 'was on'],
                'answer': 'is at'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Fatima, Umma and I __________ good friends.',
                'options': ['am', 'was', 'are', 'been'],
                'answer': 'are'
            },
            {
                'question': 'I __________ my mobile phone yesterday.',
                'options': ['loss', 'loose', 'lose', 'lost'],
                'answer': 'lost'
            }


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MATHEMATICS-1',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The pth derivative of a qth degree monic polynomial, where p, q are positive integers and 2p4 + 3pq3⁄2 = 3q3⁄2 + 2qp3 is given by?',
                        'options': ['Cannot be generally determined', '(q – 1)!', '(q)!', '(q – 1)! * pq'],
                        'answer': '(q)!'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The first and second derivatives of a quadratic Polynomial at x = 1 are 1 and 2 respectively. Then the value of f(1) – f(0) Is given by?',
                'options': ['3/2', '1/2', '1', '0'],
                'answer': '0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Mathematically, the functions in Green’s theorem will be',
                'options': ['Continuous derivatives', 'Discrete derivatives', 'Continuous partial derivatives', 'Discrete partial derivatives'],
                'answer': 'Continuous partial derivatives'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Find the value of Green’s theorem for F = x2 and G = y2 is',
                'options': ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
                'answer': '0'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not an application of Green’s theorem?',
                'options': ['Solving two dimensional flow integrals', 'Area surveying', 'Volume of plane figures', 'Centroid of plane figures'],
                'answer': 'Volume of plane figures'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Calculate the Green’s value for the functions F = y2 and G = x2 for the region x = 1 and y = 2 from origin.',
                'options': ['0', '2', '-2', '1'],
                'answer': '-2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Solution of the differential equation sec2 x tan⁡y dx + sec2 y tan⁡x dy=0 is _______',
                'options': ['(sec x. sec y)=k', '(sec x .tany)=k', '(tan x. tany)=k', '(sec x .tan x)+(sec y .tan y)=k'],
                'answer': '(tan x. tany)=k'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Taylor’s theorem is mainly used in expressing the function as sum with infinite terms.',
                'options': ['True', 'False', 'Both', 'None'],
                'answer': 'True'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The jacobian of p,q,r w.r.t x,y,z given p=x+y+z, q=y+z, r=z is ________',
                'options': ['0', '1', '2', '-1'],
                'answer': '1'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Maximize the function x + y – z = 1 with respect to the constraint xy=36.',
                'options': ['0', '8', '-8', 'No Maxima exists'],
                'answer': 'No Maxima exists'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'COMPUTER PROGRAMMING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Why do variable names beginning with the underscore is not encouraged?',
                        'options': ['It is not standardized', 'To avoid conflicts since assemblers and loaders use such names', 'To avoid conflicts since library routines use such names', 'To avoid conflicts with environment variables of an operating system'],
                        'answer': 'To avoid conflicts since library routines use such names'
            },
            {
                'question': 'All keywords in C are in ____________',
                'options': ['LowerCase letters', 'UpperCase letters', 'CamelCase letters', 'None of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'LowerCase letters'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a valid variable name declaration?',
                'options': ['int _a3;', 'int a_3;', 'int 3_a;', 'int _3a;'],
                'answer': 'int 3_a;'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a User-defined data type?',
                'options': ['typedef int Boolean;', 'typedef enum {Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri} Workdays;', 'struct {char name[10], int age};', 'all of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'all of the mentioned'
            },

            {
                'question': 'What is short int in C programming?',
                'options': ['The basic data type of C', 'Qualifier', 'Short is the qualifier and int is the basic data type', 'All of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'Short is the qualifier and int is the basic data type'
            },
            {
                'question': 'enum types are processed by _________',
                'options': ['Compiler', 'Preprocessor', 'Linker', 'Assembler'],
                'answer': 'Compiler'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following statement is false?',
                'options': ['Constant variables need not be defined as they are declared and can be defined later', 'Global constant variables are initialized to zero', 'const keyword is used to define constant values', 'You cannot reassign a value to a constant variable'],
                'answer': 'Constant variables need not be defined as they are declared and can be defined later'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following declaration is illegal?',
                'options': ['char *str = “C programming”;', 'char str[] = “C programming”;', 'char str[20] = “C programming”;', 'char[] str = “C programming”;'],
                'answer': 'char[] str = “C programming”;'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A variable declared in a function can be used in main().',
                'options': ['True', 'False', 'True if it is declared static', 'None of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'False'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which of the following statement is false?',
                'options': [' A variable defined once can be defined again with different scope', 'A single variable cannot be defined with two different types in the same scope', 'A variable must be declared and defined at the same time', 'A variable refers to a location in memory'],
                'answer': 'A variable must be declared and defined at the same time'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING PHYSICS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following is a unique property of laser?',
                        'options': ['Directional', 'Speed', 'Coherence', 'Wavelength'],
                        'answer': 'Coherence'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Calculate the wavelength of radiation emitted by an LED made up of a semiconducting material with band gap energy 2.8eV.',
                'options': ['2.8 Å', '4.3308 Å', '5548.4 Å', ''],
                'answer': '4430.8 Å'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the principle of fibre optical communication?',
                'options': ['Frequency modulation', 'Population inversion', 'Total internal reflection', 'Doppler Effect'],
                'answer': 'Total internal reflection'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The walls of a particle in a box are supposed to be ____________',
                'options': ['Small but infinitely hard', 'Infinitely large but soft', 'Soft and Small', 'Infinitely hard and infinitely large'],
                'answer': 'Infinitely hard and infinitely large'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The wave function of the particle lies in which region?',
                'options': ['x > 0', 'x < 0', '0 < X < L', 'x > L'],
                'answer': '0 < X < L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a particle inside a box, the potential is maximum at x = ___________',
                'options': ['L', '2L', 'L/2', '3L'],
                'answer': 'L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Calculate the Zero-point energy for a particle in an infinite potential well for an electron confined to a 1 nm atom.',
                'options': ['3.9 X 10-29 J', '4.9 X 10-29 J', '5.9 X 10-29 J', '6.9 X 10-29 J'],
                'answer': '5.9 X 10-29 J'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Below transition temperature, the electrical resistance of the superconductor is _________________',
                'options': ['Finite', 'Large', 'Zero', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Zero'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The temperature at which the conductivity of material becomes infinite is called ________________',
                'options': ['Critical temperature', 'Absolute temperature', 'Mean temperature', 'Crystallization temperature'],
                'answer': 'Critical temperature'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The minimum amount of current passed through the body of the superconductor in order to destroy the superconductivity is called __________',
                'options': ['Normal current', 'Critical current', 'Eddy current', 'Hall current'],
                'answer': 'Critical current'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING DRAWING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The angle which we can’t make using a single Set-square is ________',
                        'options': ['45', '60', '30', '75'],
                        'answer': '75'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following instrument can be used to draw accurate perpendicular lines, parallel lines and angular lines?',
                'options': ['Mini – drafter', 'T – square', 'Protractor', 'Set square'],
                'answer': 'Mini – drafter'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For what purpose the lead is sharpened to chisel point?',
                'options': ['To draw long thin lines with uniform thickness', 'To draw long thin lines with non-uniform thickness', 'For sketch works and lettering', 'For drawing thick lines with non-uniform thickness'],
                'answer': 'To draw long thin lines with uniform thickness'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A mini drafter helps in __________',
                'options': ['Drawing parallel and perpendicular lines', 'Drawing smooth curves', 'Drawing circles', 'Measuring the length of a curve'],
                'answer': 'Drawing parallel and perpendicular lines'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The identification symbol of the spherical radius is _________',
                'options': ['SR', 'Sq', 'Sᴓ', 'SP'],
                'answer': 'SR'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Why do we need engineering drawing standards?',
                'options': ['To eliminate the originality/creativity of drafter', 'To modify and organize a way of drafting', 'To have effective communication of drawings', 'To eliminate mistakes'],
                'answer': 'To have effective communication of drawings'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In engineering drawings, the three-view multi-view drawing is standard. What are the collections of three-view drawings?',
                'options': ['The top, front, and the left-side views', 'The front, bottom and the right-side views', 'The bottom, rare and the top views', 'The top, front and the right side views'],
                'answer': 'The top, front and the right side views'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the object is placed in the first quadrant, the projected view results in the ____',
                'options': ['First-angle projection', 'Second-angle projection', 'Third-angle projection', 'Fourth-angle projection'],
                'answer': 'First-angle projection'
            },

            {
                'question': 'In third angle projection, the projections of the object are in the ______ direction of the ray of sight.',
                'options': ['Same', 'Opposite', 'Upward', 'Downward'],
                'answer': 'Opposite'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the type of scale in which the representative fraction is 1:1?',
                'options': ['Enlarged scale', 'Reduced scale', 'Full size scale', 'Graphical scale'],
                'answer': 'Full size scale'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING PHYSICS LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following is a unique property of laser?',
                        'options': ['Directional', 'Speed', 'Coherence', 'Wavelength'],
                        'answer': 'Coherence'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Calculate the wavelength of radiation emitted by an LED made up of a semiconducting material with band gap energy 2.8eV.',
                'options': ['2.8 Å', '4.3308 Å', '5548.4 Å', ''],
                'answer': '4430.8 Å'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the principle of fibre optical communication?',
                'options': ['Frequency modulation', 'Population inversion', 'Total internal reflection', 'Doppler Effect'],
                'answer': 'Total internal reflection'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The walls of a particle in a box are supposed to be ____________',
                'options': ['Small but infinitely hard', 'Infinitely large but soft', 'Soft and Small', 'Infinitely hard and infinitely large'],
                'answer': 'Infinitely hard and infinitely large'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The wave function of the particle lies in which region?',
                'options': ['x > 0', 'x < 0', '0 < X < L', 'x > L'],
                'answer': '0 < X < L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a particle inside a box, the potential is maximum at x = ___________',
                'options': ['L', '2L', 'L/2', '3L'],
                'answer': 'L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Calculate the Zero-point energy for a particle in an infinite potential well for an electron confined to a 1 nm atom.',
                'options': ['3.9 X 10-29 J', '4.9 X 10-29 J', '5.9 X 10-29 J', '6.9 X 10-29 J'],
                'answer': '5.9 X 10-29 J'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Below transition temperature, the electrical resistance of the superconductor is _________________',
                'options': ['Finite', 'Large', 'Zero', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Zero'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The temperature at which the conductivity of material becomes infinite is called ________________',
                'options': ['Critical temperature', 'Absolute temperature', 'Mean temperature', 'Crystallization temperature'],
                'answer': 'Critical temperature'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The minimum amount of current passed through the body of the superconductor in order to destroy the superconductivity is called __________',
                'options': ['Normal current', 'Critical current', 'Eddy current', 'Hall current'],
                'answer': 'Critical current'
            }


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'COMPUTER PROGRAMMING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'what is the first step in the software development lifecycle ?',
                        'options': ['system Design', 'coding', 'system Testing', 'preliminary Investigation and Analysis'],
                        'answer': 'preliminary Investigation and Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does the study of an existing system refer to?',
                'options': ['Details of DFD', 'Feasibility Study', 'System Analysis', 'System Planning'],
                'answer': 'System Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does RAD stand for?',
                'options': ['Rapid Application Document', 'Rapid Application Development', 'Relative Application Development', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Rapid Application Development'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The system by which companies are managed and controlled is known as?',
                'options': ['Management', 'Strategic ', 'Corporate', '.Internal'],
                'answer': 'Corporate'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Human Resource Management is ?',
                'options': ['Employee oriented', 'Employer oriented', 'Legally oriented', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Employer oriented'
            },

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGLISH LANGUAGE COMMUNICATION SKILLS LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'It was raining yesterday, so we __________ out.',
                        'options': ['did not go', 'did not went', 'would not go', 'would not gone'],
                        'answer': 'did not go'
            },
            {
                'question': ' I __________ what was happening.',
                'options': ['couldn’t understood', 'couldn’t understand', 'was not able to understood', 'would not able to understand'],
                'answer': 'couldn’t understand'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If you work hard, you __________ good marks.',
                'options': ['would get', 'would got', 'will get', 'will got'],
                'answer': 'will get'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If you __________ hard, you would not have failed in the exam.',
                'options': ['have work', 'have worked', 'had work', 'had worked'],
                'answer': 'had worked'
            },

            {
                'question': 'They will not come here, __________?',
                'options': ['won’t they', 'won’t them', 'will they', 'will them'],
                'answer': 'will they'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The newly installed application sounds very __________.',
                'options': ['interest', 'interested', 'interestingly', 'interesting'],
                'answer': 'interesting'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Our team played __________.',
                'options': ['bad', 'badly', 'good', 'well done'],
                'answer': 'badly'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Fatima is not at home at the moment, She __________ work.',
                'options': ['is at', 'is on', 'was at', 'was on'],
                'answer': 'is at'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Fatima, Umma and I __________ good friends.',
                'options': ['am', 'was', 'are', 'been'],
                'answer': 'are'
            },
            {
                'question': 'I __________ my mobile phone yesterday.',
                'options': ['loss', 'loose', 'lose', 'lost'],
                'answer': 'lost'
            }

        ]
    },
]
sem_2 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGLISH FOR PROFESSIONAL COMMUNICATION',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of these qualities are important in a group discussion?',
                        'options': ['Emotional stability', 'Hostility', 'Ignorance', 'Aggressiveness'],
                        'answer': 'Emotional stability'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of these must be avoided in a group discussion?',
                'options': ['Speaking facts', 'Asking questions', 'Speaking fast', 'Speaking with clarity'],
                'answer': 'Speaking fast'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A group discussion must advance _____',
                'options': ['truth', 'dishonesty', 'Personal glory', 'arguments'],
                'answer': 'truth'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of these must be avoided in any presentation?',
                'options': ['Proper grammar', 'Complex words', 'Short sentences', 'Clear voice'],
                'answer': 'Complex words'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Reports present conclusions based on:',
                'options': ['belief', 'impression', 'investigation', 'intuition'],
                'answer': 'investigation'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The terms of reference for producing a specific report are given by the:',
                'options': ['reader', 'writer', 'organization', 'expert'],
                'answer': 'organization'
            },
            {
                'question': 'I don’t ______ much sympathy with students who fail because they did not study.',
                'options': ['do', 'have', 'make', 'none'],
                'answer': 'have'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the part of the sentence which denotes the person or thing about which something is said?',
                'options': ['Predicate', 'Subject', 'Phrase', 'Clause'],
                'answer': 'Subject'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the clause in: Neha played when evening came.',
                'options': ['Neha played', 'Played when evening', 'When evening came', 'Evening came'],
                'answer': 'When evening came'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of these is not a type of subordinate clause?',
                'options': ['Adverb', 'Verb', 'Adjective', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Verb'
            },


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MATHEMATICS-2',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Find the Laplace transform of δ(t).',
                        'options': ['1', '0', 'Infinite', '2'],
                        'answer': '1'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A “periodic function” is given by a function which',
                'options': ['has a period T = 2π', 'satisfies f (t + T) = f (t)', 'satisfies f (t + T) = − f (t)', 'has a period T = π'],
                'answer': 'satisfies f (t + T) = f (t)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Any waveform can be expressed in Fourier series if',
                'options': ['Sampling conditions are satisfied', 'Dirchiet conditions are satisfied', 'Maxwells conditions are satisfied', 'None of the above conditions is required to be satisfied'],
                'answer': 'Dirchiet conditions are satisfied'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Fourier series expansion of an even period function contains',
                'options': ['Only cosine terms', 'Cosine terms and a constant', 'Only sine terms', 'Sine terms and a constant'],
                'answer': 'Only cosine terms'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Fourier series expansion of an odd periodic function contains',
                'options': ['Cosine terms', 'Constant terms only', 'Sine terms', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Sine terms'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An example for a function which neither even nor odd',
                'options': ['xsinx', 'e^(ax)', 'cosx', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'e^(ax)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is a property of Fourier transform?',
                'options': ['Linearity', 'Scaling', 'Differentiation', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Laplace transform any function changes it domain to s-domain.',
                'options': ['True', 'False', 'Both', 'None'],
                'answer': 'True'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Laplace transform if sin⁡(at)u(t) is?',
                'options': ['s ⁄ a2+s2', 'a ⁄ a2+s2', 's2 ⁄ a2+s2', 'a2 ⁄ a2+s2'],
                'answer': 'a ⁄ a2+s2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Value of ∫∞−∞etSin(t)dt = ?',
                'options': ['Sum of infinite integers', 'Sum of infinite factorials', 'Sum of squares of Integers', 'Sum of square of factorials'],
                'answer': 'Sum of infinite factorials'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA STRUCTURES',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'How do you initialize an array in C?',
                        'options': ['int arr[3] = (1,2,3);', 'int arr(3) = {1,2,3};', 'int arr[3] = {1,2,3};', 'int arr(3) = (1,2,3);'],
                        'answer': 'int arr[3] = {1,2,3};'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In general, the index of the first element in an array is __________',
                'options': ['0', '-1', '1', '2'],
                'answer': '0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Elements in an array are accessed _____________',
                'options': ['randomly', 'sequentially', 'exponentially', 'logarithmically'],
                'answer': 'randomly'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Process of inserting an element in stack is called ____________',
                'options': ['Create', 'Push', 'Evaluation', 'Pop'],
                'answer': 'Push'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In a stack, if a user tries to remove an element from an empty stack it is called _________',
                'options': ['Underflow', 'Empty collection', 'Overflow', 'Garbage Collection'],
                'answer': 'Underflow'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not the application of stack?',
                'options': ['A parentheses balancing program', 'Tracking of local variables at run time', 'Compiler Syntax Analyzer', 'Data Transfer between two asynchronous process'],
                'answer': 'Data Transfer between two asynchronous process'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the value of the postfix expression 6 3 2 4 + – *?',
                'options': ['1', '40', '74', '-18'],
                'answer': '-18'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In linked list each node contains a minimum of two fields. One field is data field to store the data second field is?',
                'options': ['Pointer to character', 'Pointer to integer', 'Pointer to node', 'Node'],
                'answer': 'Pointer to node'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is false about a binary search tree?',
                'options': ['The left child is always lesser than its parent', 'The right child is always greater than its parent', 'The left and right sub-trees should also be binary search trees', 'In order sequence gives decreasing order of elements'],
                'answer': 'In order sequence gives decreasing order of elements'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following properties is associated with a queue?',
                'options': ['First In Last Out', 'First In First Out', 'Last In First Out', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'First In First Out'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following polymer type is not classified on the basis of its application and properties?',
                        'options': ['rubbers', 'plastics', 'fibres', 'synthetic'],
                        'answer': 'synthetic'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a thermosetting polymer?',
                'options': ['polystyrene', 'polyolefins', 'nylons', 'phenolic resins'],
                'answer': 'phenolic resins'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which tree gives out the latex to obtain natural rubber?',
                'options': ['eucalyptus', 'hevea brasiliensis', 'anogeissus', 'astragalus'],
                'answer': 'hevea brasiliensis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What are the sequential processes through which rubber latex undergo to give natural rubber?',
                'options': ['tapping-preservation-coagulation', 'preservation-tapping-coagulation', 'tapping-coagulation-preservation', 'coagulation-tapping-preservation'],
                'answer': 'tapping-preservation-coagulation'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Both temporary and permanent hardness of water can be removed by',
                'options': ['boiling', 'distillation', 'filtration', 'decantation'],
                'answer': 'distillation'
            },
            {
                'question': 'When temporary hard water is boiled, one of the substances formed is',
                'options': ['calcium bicarbonate', 'calcium sulfate', 'hydrogen chloride', 'carbon dioxide'],
                'answer': 'carbon dioxide'
            },
            {
                'question': 'When heating one end of a metal plate, the other end gets hot because of',
                'options': ['the resistance of the metal', 'mobility of atoms in the metal', 'energised electrons moving to the other end', 'minor perturbation in the energy of atoms'],
                'answer': 'energised electrons moving to the other end'
            },
            {
                'question': 'On electrolysis of dilute sulphuric acid using platinum electrodes, the product obtained at the anode will be',
                'options': ['hydrogen', 'oxygen', 'hydrogen sulphide', 'sulphur dioxide'],
                'answer': 'oxygen'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In presence of which gas is the fuel burnt to generate energy in the form of heat?',
                'options': ['Oxygen', 'Hydrogen', 'Methane', 'Nitrogen'],
                'answer': 'Oxygen'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which are the main constituents of fuel from given options?',
                'options': ['Carbon and Nitrogen', 'Oxygen and Hydrogen', 'Carbon and Hydrogen', 'Helium and Oxygen'],
                'answer': 'Carbon and Hydrogen'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENVIRONMENTAL STUDIES',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which layer of the atmosphere contains the ozone responsible for the absorption of UV (Ultra-Violet) light?',
                        'options': ['Stratosphere', 'Troposphere', 'Mesosphere', 'None of these'],
                        'answer': 'Stratosphere'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The estimated percentage of the forest land that ideally India should have is:',
                'options': ['50%', '15%', '33%', '44%'],
                'answer': '33%'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The essential non-metallic minerals are:',
                'options': ['Granite, marble, limestone', 'Gold, silver, platinum', 'Iron, aluminum, zinc, copper', 'Coal, clay, cement, silica'],
                'answer': 'Coal, clay, cement, silica'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which element is considered the largest source of world\'s commercial energy consumption?',
                'options': ['Coal', 'Oil', 'Naural Gas', 'Methane'],
                'answer': 'Oil'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What are the two forms of alcohol are included in biofuels?',
                'options': ['Ethanol and methanol', 'Ethanol and propanol', 'Ethanol and propanol', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Ethanol and methanol'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the world\'s largest potential source of biomass energy?',
                'options': ['Animal waste', 'Industrial waste', 'Fibrous waste of the paper industry', 'Fibrous waste of the sugar industry'],
                'answer': 'Fibrous waste of the sugar industry'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The functional aspects of the ecosystem are:',
                'options': ['Energy cycles', 'Nutrient cycles', 'Food chains', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which human activity can decreases the oxygen levels present in the atmosphere?',
                'options': ['Deforestation', 'Animal hunting', 'Mining', 'Both (a) and (c)'],
                'answer': 'Deforestation'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A large number of interlinked chains in an ecosystem together forms a:',
                'options': ['Nitrogen cycle', 'Carbon cycle', 'Food web', 'Food chain'],
                'answer': 'Food web'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The type of forests grown in the Himalayan mountain region is called:',
                'options': ['Broad-leaved forests', 'Coniferous forests', 'Deciduous forests', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Coniferous forests'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'What is the molarity of the solution of barium hydroxide, if 35 ml of 0.1 M HCl is used in the titration of 25 ml of the barium hydroxide solution?',
                        'options': [' 0.35', '0.07', '0.28', '0.14'],
                        'answer': '0.07'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is used as an indicator in the titration of a strong acid and a weak base?',
                'options': ['Phenolphthalein', 'Thymol blue', 'Fluorescein', 'Methyl orange'],
                'answer': 'Methyl orange'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The ideal indicator for the titration of strong acid and weak base should have pH range between',
                'options': ['5-8', '4-6', '8-10', '7-9'],
                'answer': '4-6'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A difference between strong and weak acid is',
                'options': ['presence and absence of halogen ions', 'negative and positive pH', 'complete and partial ionisation', 'proton donation and electron acceptance'],
                'answer': 'complete and partial ionisation'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Find the concentration of HCl, if 10 ml of 0.5 M Ca(OH)2 is required to titrate 50 ml of HCl.',
                'options': ['5 M', '1/10 M', '10 M', '1/5 M'],
                'answer': '1/5 M'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the concentration of the sulphuric acid solution, if 100 ml of the solution is neutralised by 50 ml of 0.5 M Ba(OH)2 solution?',
                'options': ['0.25 M', '50 M', '0.5 M', '100 M'],
                'answer': '0.25 M'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If 30 ml of acid is neutralised by 15 ml of 0.2 N alkali, then the concentration of acid is',
                'options': ['0.4 N', '0.1 N', '0.3 N', '0.15 N'],
                'answer': '0.1 N'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a buffer solution?',
                'options': ['H2SO4 + CuSO4', 'CH3COOH + CH3COONH4', 'NaCl + NaOH', 'CH3COONa + CH3COOH'],
                'answer': ''
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is used as an indicator in the titration of a weak acid and a strong base?',
                'options': ['Bromothymol blue (6 to 7.5)', 'Methyl orange (3 to 4)', 'Methyl red (5 to 6)', 'Phenolphthalein (8 to 9.6)'],
                'answer': 'Phenolphthalein (8 to 9.6)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following titrations will have the equivalence point at a pH more than 8?',
                'options': ['HCl and NH3', 'CH3COOH and NH3', 'HCl and NaOH', 'CH3COOH and NaOH'],
                'answer': 'CH3COOH and NaOH'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA STRUCTURES LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'How do you initialize an array in C?',
                        'options': ['int arr[3] = (1,2,3);', 'int arr(3) = {1,2,3};', 'int arr[3] = {1,2,3};', 'int arr(3) = (1,2,3);'],
                        'answer': 'int arr[3] = {1,2,3};'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In general, the index of the first element in an array is __________',
                'options': ['0', '-1', '1', '2'],
                'answer': '0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Elements in an array are accessed _____________',
                'options': ['randomly', 'sequentially', 'exponentially', 'logarithmically'],
                'answer': 'randomly'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Process of inserting an element in stack is called ____________',
                'options': ['Create', 'Push', 'Evaluation', 'Pop'],
                'answer': 'Push'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In a stack, if a user tries to remove an element from an empty stack it is called _________',
                'options': ['Underflow', 'Empty collection', 'Overflow', 'Garbage Collection'],
                'answer': 'Underflow'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not the application of stack?',
                'options': ['A parentheses balancing program', 'Tracking of local variables at run time', 'Compiler Syntax Analyzer', 'Data Transfer between two asynchronous process'],
                'answer': 'Data Transfer between two asynchronous process'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the value of the postfix expression 6 3 2 4 + – *?',
                'options': ['1', '40', '74', '-18'],
                'answer': '-18'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In linked list each node contains a minimum of two fields. One field is data field to store the data second field is?',
                'options': ['Pointer to character', 'Pointer to integer', 'Pointer to node', 'Node'],
                'answer': 'Pointer to node'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is false about a binary search tree?',
                'options': ['The left child is always lesser than its parent', 'The right child is always greater than its parent', 'The left and right sub-trees should also be binary search trees', 'In order sequence gives decreasing order of elements'],
                'answer': 'In order sequence gives decreasing order of elements'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following properties is associated with a queue?',
                'options': ['First In Last Out', 'First In First Out', 'Last In First Out', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'First In First Out'
            }



        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ENGINEERING AND it WORKSHOP',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which file is used in carpentry shop?',
                        'options': ['flat file', 'half round file', 'rasp file', 'none of these'],
                        'answer': 'rasp file'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following tool is used to make the surface plain?',
                'options': ['metal jack plane', 'mallet', 'try square', 'none of these'],
                'answer': 'metal jack plane'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Try square is a ________',
                'options': ['marking tool', 'measuring tool', 'both 1 and 2', 'none'],
                'answer': 'both 1 and 2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a cutting tool?',
                'options': ['chisel', 'rip saw', 'file', 'try square'],
                'answer': 'try square'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Fitting vice is a _______.',
                'options': ['holding vice for metals', 'holding vice for woods', 'cutting device', 'measuring device'],
                'answer': 'holding vice for metals'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The virus that spread in application software is called as',
                'options': ['Boot virus', 'Macro virus', 'File virus', 'Anti virus'],
                'answer': 'Macro virus'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Where data is recorded in a floppy disk',
                'options': ['Sectors', 'Runs', 'Tracks', 'Rounders'],
                'answer': 'Tracks'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An electronic device that converts data into information and processes it',
                'options': ['Computer', 'Processor', 'Case', 'Stylus'],
                'answer': 'Computer'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which standard govern parallel communications?',
                'options': ['IEEE 1284', 'RS232', 'CAT 5', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'IEEE 1284'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which peripheral port provides the fastest throughput to laser printers',
                'options': ['SCSI', 'Serial', 'Parallel', 'RS-232'],
                'answer': 'RS-232'
            }

        ]
    },
]
sem_3 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'MATHEMATICS-3',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The first and second derivatives of a quadratic Polynomial at x = 1 are 1 and 2 respectively. Then the value of f(1) – f(0) Is given by?',
                        'options': ['Cannot be generally determined', '(q – 1)!', '(q)!', '(q – 1)! * pq'],
                        'answer': ' (q)!'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The first and second derivatives of a quadratic Polynomial at x = 1 are 1 and 2 respectively. Then the value of f(1) – f(0) Is given by?',
                'options': ['3⁄2', '1⁄2', '1', '0'],
                'answer': '0'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Let f(x) = x9 ex then the ninth derivative of f(x) at x = 0 is given by?',
                'options': [' 9!', ' 9! * e9', '10!', '21!'],
                'answer': '9!'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The first, second and third derivatives of a cubic polynomial f(x) at x = 1, are 13, 23 and 33 respectively. Then the value of f(0) + f(1) – 2f(-1) is?',
                'options': ['76', '86', '126', '41.5'],
                'answer': '41.5'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Let g(x) = ln(x) ⁄ x – 1 Then the hundredth derivative at x = 1 is?',
                'options': ['100!⁄101', '99!⁄101', '101⁄100!', ' 1⁄99!'],
                'answer': '100!⁄101'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If A is Hermitian Matrix then iA  is ',
                'options': ['Unitary ', 'Skew-Hemitian', 'Hermitian ', 'Orthogonal'],
                'answer': 'Skew-Hemitian'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The eigen values of real symmetric matrix are  ',
                'options': ['imaginary', '0', 'real', 'none'],
                'answer': 'real'
            },
            {
                'question': 'fit a curve   is y=a+bx+cx2',
                'options': ['Transcedental', 'parabola', 'exponential', 'none'],
                'answer': 'parabola'
            },
            {
                'question': '∆ is know as ',
                'options': ['Averaging operator', 'Forward difference operator ', 'Backword difference operator', 'Displacement operator'],
                'answer': 'Forward difference operator'
            },
            {
                'question': '∇ is know as',
                'options': ['Averaging operator', 'Forward difference operator ', 'Backword difference operator', 'Displacement operator'],
                'answer': 'Backword difference operator'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following is generally used for performing tasks like creating the structure of the relations, deleting relation?',
                        'options': ['DML(Data Manipulation Language', 'Query', 'Relational Schema', 'DDL(Data Definition Language)'],
                        'answer': 'DDL(Data Definition Language)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What do you mean by one to many relationships?',
                'options': ['One class may have many teachers', 'One teacher can have many classes', 'Many classes may have many teachers', 'Many teachers may have many classes'],
                'answer': 'One teacher can have many classes'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A Database Management System is a type of _________software.',
                'options': ['It is a type of system software', 'It is a kind of application software', 'It is a kind of general software', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'It is a type of system software'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The term "FAT" is stands for_____',
                'options': ['File Allocation Tree', 'File Allocation Table', 'File Allocation Graph', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'File Allocation Table'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by FAT?',
                'options': ['8GB', '4GB', '4TB', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': '4GB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' The term "NTFS" refers to which one of the following?',
                'options': ['New Technology File System', 'New Tree File System', 'New Table type File System', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'New Technology File System'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by NTFS?',
                'options': ['4GB', '16TB', '64TB', '8TB'],
                'answer': '4GB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' A huge collection of the information or data accumulated form several different sources is known as ________:',
                'options': ['Data Management', 'Data Mining', 'Data Warehouse', 'Both B and C'],
                'answer': 'Data Mining'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following can be used to extract or filter the data & information from the data warehouse?',
                'options': ['Data redundancy', 'Data recovery tool', 'Data mining', 'Both B and C'],
                'answer': 'Data mining'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which one of the following refers to the "data about data"?',
                'options': ['Directory', 'Sub Data', 'Warehouse', 'Meta Data'],
                'answer': 'Meta Data'
            },
        ]
    },


    {
        'subject_name': 'DISCRETE MATHEMATICS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'If x is a set and the set contains an integer which is neither positive nor negative then the set x is ____________.',
                        'options': ['Set is Empty', 'Set is Non-empty', 'Set is Finite.', 'Set is both Non- empty and Finite.'],
                        'answer': 'Set is both Non- empty and Finite.'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If x ∈ N and x is prime, then x is ________ set.',
                'options': ['Infinite set', 'Finite set', 'Empty set', 'Not a set'],
                'answer': 'Infinite set'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If x is a set and the set contains the real number between 1 and 2, then the set is ________.',
                'options': ['Empty set', 'Finite set', 'Infinite set', 'None of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'Infinite set'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a subset of set {1, 2, 3, 4}?',
                'options': ['{1, 2}', '{1, 2, 3}', '{1,3}', 'All of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'All of the mentioned'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Convert the set x in roster form if set x contains the positive prime number, which divides 72.',
                'options': ['{∅}', '{2, 3}', '{2, 3, 7}', '{3, 5, 7}'],
                'answer': '{2, 3}'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Power set of empty or Null set has exactly _________ subset.',
                'options': ['One', 'Two', 'Zero', 'Three'],
                'answer': 'One'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the Cartesian product of set A and set B, if the set A = {1, 2} and set B = {a, b}?',
                'options': ['{ (1, a), (1, b), (2, a), (b, b) }', '{ (1, 1), (2, 2), (a, a), (b, b) }', '{ (1, a), (2, a), (1, b), (2, b) }', '{ (1, 1), (a, a), (2, a), (1, b) }'],
                'answer': '{ (1, a), (2, a), (1, b), (2, b) }'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The intersection of the sets {1, 2, 8, 9, 10, 5} and {1, 2, 6, 10, 12, 15} is the set _____________',
                'options': ['{1, 2, 10}', '{5, 6, 12, 15}', '{2, 5, 10, 9}', 'sd) {1, 6, 12, 9, 8}'],
                'answer': '{1, 2, 10}'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The difference of {1, 2, 3, 6, 8} and {1, 2, 5, 6} is the set ____________',
                'options': ['{1, 3}', '{5, 6, 8}', '{3, 8}', '{2, 6, 5}'],
                'answer': '{3, 8}'
            },
            {
                'question': ' If n(A) = 20 and n(B) = 30 and n(A U B) = 40 then n(A ∩ B) is?',
                'options': ['20', '030', '40', '10'],
                'answer': '10'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'BASIC ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': ' Among the following, which is the right formula for inductance?',
                        'options': [' L=emf*t/I', 'L=emf/t*I', 'L=emf*I/t', 'L=emf*t*I'],
                        'answer': ' L=emf*t/I'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Among the following, which is the right formula for inductance of N turns?',
                'options': [' L=et/Ni', 'L=N*i *e*t', 'L=Ni/et', ' L=N/iet'],
                'answer': ' L=et/Ni'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a coil having a magnetic circuit of constant reluctance, the flux is ___________ to the current.',
                'options': ['Directly proportional', 'Inversely proportional', 'Not related', 'Very large compared to'],
                'answer': 'Directly proportional'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a coil having a magnetic circuit of constant reluctance, if the flux increases, what happens to the current?',
                'options': ['Increases', ' Decreases', ' Remains constant', 'Becomes zero'],
                'answer': ' Increases'
            },
            {
                'question': '. The unit for inductance is ___________',
                'options': [' Ohm', 'Henry', ' A/m', 'A/s'],
                'answer': 'Henry'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 5A to 3A in 2 seconds and the inductance is 10H, calculate the emf.',
                'options': ['5v', '10v', '15v', '20v'],
                'answer': '10v'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 5A to 3A in x sec and inductance is 10H. The emf is 10V, calculate the value of x.',
                'options': ['2s', '3s', '4s', '5s'],
                'answer': '2s'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 3A to 5A in 2s and the emf is 10V. Calculate the inductance.',
                'options': ['10h', '20h', '30h', '40h'],
                'answer': '10h'
            },
            {
                'question': 'unit of power?',
                'options': ['watt', 'ohm', 'amp', 'none'],
                'answer': 'watt'
            },
            {
                'question': 'unit of resistence?',
                'options': ['ohm', 'watt', 'amp', 'none'],
                'answer': 'ohm'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DIGITAL LOGIC AND DESIGN',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The minterm expansion of f(P, Q, R) = PQ + QR\'',
                        'options': ['m2 + m4 + m6 + m7', 'm0 + m1 + m3 + m5', 'm0 + m1 + m6 + m7', 'm2 + m3 + m4 + m5'],
                        'answer': 'm2 + m4 + m6 + m7'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the minimum number of gates required to implement the Boolean function (AB+C)if we have to use only 2-input NOR gates?',
                'options': ['2', '3', '4', '5'],
                'answer': '3'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Let r denote number system radix. The only value(s) of r that satisfy the equation 12',
                'options': ['decimal 10', 'decimal 11', 'decimal 10 and 11', 'any value > 2'],
                'answer': 'any value > 2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If P, Q, R are Boolean variables, then (P + Q\')(PQ\' + PR)(P\'R\' + Q\') simplifies',
                'options': ['PQ\'', 'PR\'', 'PQ\' + R', 'PR\'\' + Q'],
                'answer': 'PQ\''
            },

            {
                'question': 'Let f(A, B) = A\' + B. Simplified expression for function f(f(x + y, y)z) is :',
                'options': ['x\' + z', 'xyz', 'xy\' + z', 'none'],
                'answer': 'xy\' + z'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The minimum number of JK flip-flops required to construct a synchronous counter with the count sequence (0, 0, 1, 1, 2, 2, 3, 3, 0, 0,...) is _______',
                'options': ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
                'answer': '3'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The total number of prime implicants of the function f(w, x, y, z) = Σ(0, 2, 4, 5, 6, 10) is ________.',
                'options': ['2', '3', '4', '5'],
                'answer': '3'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the minimum number of NAND gates required to implement a 2-input EXCLUSIVE-OR function without using any other logic gate?',
                'options': ['3', '4', '5', '6'],
                'answer': '4'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Using a 4-bit 2’s complement arithmetic, which of the following additions will result in an overflow? (i) 1100 + 1100 (ii) 0011 + 0111 (iii) 1111 + 0111',
                'options': ['(i) only', '(ii) only', 'iii) only', '(i) and (iii) only'],

                'answer': '(ii) only'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MANAGERIAL ECONOMICS AND FINANCIAL ANALYSIS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Demand is determined by',
                        'options': ['Price of the product', 'Relative prices of other goods', 'Tastes and habits', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'When a firm’s average revenue is equal to its average cost, it gets ________.',
                'options': ['Super profit', 'Normal profit', 'Sub normal profit', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Normal profit'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Managerial economics generally refers to the integration of economic theory with business',
                'options': ['Ethics', 'Management', 'Practice', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'Practice'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Given the price, if the cost of production increases because of higher price of raw materials, the supply',
                'options': ['Decreases', 'Increases', 'Remains same', 'Any of the above'],
                'answer': 'Decreases'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The cost recorded in the books of accounts are considered as',
                'options': ['Total cost', 'Marginal cost', 'Average cost', 'Explicit cost'],
                'answer': 'Explicit cost'
            },
            {
                'question': '-A Joint Stock Company is managed by the Board of Directors elected by _____ .',
                'options': ['Top management', 'Shareholders', 'Employees of company', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Shareholders'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Under perfect competition, price is determined by the interaction of total demand and ________',
                'options': ['Total supply', 'Total cost', 'Total utility', 'Total production'],
                'answer': 'Total supply'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The out of pocket costs are ________.',
                'options': ['Sunk costs', 'Marginal costs', 'Explicit costs', 'Social costs'],
                'answer': 'Marginal costs'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The short run Average Cost curve is __ shaped',
                'options': ['v', 'u', 'L', 's'],
                'answer': 'u'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The demand curve has a _____ slope.',
                'options': ['Undefined', 'Zero c', 'Negative', 'Positive'],
                'answer': 'Positive'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA BASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following is generally used for performing tasks like creating the structure of the relations, deleting relation?',
                        'options': ['DML(Data Manipulation Language', 'Query', 'Relational Schema', 'DDL(Data Definition Language)'],
                        'answer': 'DDL(Data Definition Language)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What do you mean by one to many relationships?',
                'options': ['One class may have many teachers', 'One teacher can have many classes', 'Many classes may have many teachers', 'Many teachers may have many classes'],
                'answer': 'One teacher can have many classes'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A Database Management System is a type of _________software.',
                'options': ['It is a type of system software', 'It is a kind of application software', 'It is a kind of general software', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'It is a type of system software'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The term "FAT" is stands for_____',
                'options': ['File Allocation Tree', 'File Allocation Table', 'File Allocation Graph', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'File Allocation Table'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by FAT?',
                'options': ['8GB', '4GB', '4TB', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': '4GB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' The term "NTFS" refers to which one of the following?',
                'options': ['New Technology File System', 'New Tree File System', 'New Table type File System', 'Both A and C'],
                'answer': 'New Technology File System'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by NTFS?',
                'options': ['4GB', '16TB', '64TB', '8TB'],
                'answer': '4GB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' A huge collection of the information or data accumulated form several different sources is known as ________:',
                'options': ['Data Management', 'Data Mining', 'Data Warehouse', 'Both B and C'],
                'answer': ''
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following can be used to extract or filter the data & information from the data warehouse?',
                'options': ['Data redundancy', 'Data recovery tool', 'Data mining', 'Both B and C'],
                'answer': 'Data mining'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which one of the following refers to the "data about data"?',
                'options': ['Directory', 'Sub Data', 'Warehouse', 'Meta Data'],
                'answer': 'Meta Data'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'BASIC ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': ' Among the following, which is the right formula for inductance?',
                        'options': [' L=emf*t/I', 'L=emf/t*I', 'L=emf*I/t', 'L=emf*t*I'],
                        'answer': ' L=emf*t/I'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Among the following, which is the right formula for inductance of N turns?',
                'options': [' L=et/Ni', 'L=N*i *e*t', 'L=Ni/et', ' L=N/iet'],
                'answer': ' L=et/Ni'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a coil having a magnetic circuit of constant reluctance, the flux is ___________ to the current.',
                'options': ['Directly proportional', 'Inversely proportional', 'Not related', 'Very large compared to'],
                'answer': 'Directly proportional'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For a coil having a magnetic circuit of constant reluctance, if the flux increases, what happens to the current?',
                'options': ['Increases', ' Decreases', ' Remains constant', 'Becomes zero'],
                'answer': ' Increases'
            },
            {
                'question': '. The unit for inductance is ___________',
                'options': [' Ohm', 'Henry', ' A/m', 'A/s'],
                'answer': 'Henry'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 5A to 3A in 2 seconds and the inductance is 10H, calculate the emf.',
                'options': ['5v', '10v', '15v', '20v'],
                'answer': '10v'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 5A to 3A in x sec and inductance is 10H. The emf is 10V, calculate the value of x.',
                'options': ['2s', '3s', '4s', '5s'],
                'answer': '2s'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the current changes from 3A to 5A in 2s and the emf is 10V. Calculate the inductance.',
                'options': ['10h', '20h', '30h', '40h'],
                'answer': '10h'
            },
            {
                'question': 'unit of power?',
                'options': ['watt', 'ohm', 'amp', 'none'],
                'answer': 'watt'
            },
            {
                'question': 'unit of resistence?',
                'options': ['ohm', 'watt', 'amp', 'none'],
                'answer': 'ohm'
            },
        ]
    },
]
sem_4 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'PROBABILITY AND STATISTICS ',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The Probability of drawing one ace card form cards deck=',
                        'options': ['1/13', '2/13', '1/26', '1/52'],
                        'answer': '1/26'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Maximum value of probability is',
                'options': ['0', '0.5', '1', '2'],
                'answer': '1'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If A and B are mutually exclusive events then ………..',
                'options': ['P (A∩B) = 1', 'P (A∩B) = 0', 'P (A∪B) = 0', 'none'],
                'answer': 'P (A∩B) = 0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The critical value of z at 95% confidence interval inone two tail……………',
                'options': ['2.33', '1.645', '1.96', '2.58'],
                'answer': '1.96'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The critical value of z at 90% confidence interval in right tail ……………',
                'options': ['2.33', '1.645', '1.96', '2.58'],
                'answer': '2.33'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In a t-distribution of sample size n, the degree of freedom is',
                'options': ['n+1', 'n-1', 'n', '1/n'],
                'answer': 'n-1'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the arrival rate is 3 and t6he service rate is 5 then p=---',
                'options': ['3/5', '5/3', '2/5', '5/2'],
                'answer': '3/5'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If a coin tossed twice,the probability of grtting atleast one head is--',
                'options': ['1/2', '1/4', '1/3', 'none'],
                'answer': '1'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The mean and variance of a Poisson distribution are ……',
                'options': ['not equal', 'equal', '0', 'none'],
                'answer': 'equal'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If P (E) = 1 then the event is called……………… ',
                'options': ['Impossible event', 'Certain event', 'Conditional event', 'none'],
                'answer': 'Certain event'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'SOFTWARE ENGINEERING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'What is the first step in the software development lifecycle?',
                        'options': ['System Design', 'Coding', 'System Testing', 'Preliminary Investigation and Analysis'],

                        'answer': 'Preliminary Investigation and Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does the study of an existing system refer to?',
                'options': ['Details of DFD', 'Feasibility Study', 'System Analysis', 'System Planning'],
                'answer': 'System Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is involved in the system planning and designing phase of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)?',
                'options': ['Sizing', 'Parallel run', 'Specification freeze', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does RAD stand for?',
                'options': ['Rapid Application Document', 'Rapid Application Development', 'Relative Application Development', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Rapid Application Development'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following prototypes does not associated with Prototyping Model?',
                'options': ['Domain Prototype', 'Vertical Prototype', 'Horizontal Prototype', 'Diagonal Prototype'],
                'answer': 'Diagonal Prototype'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The major drawback of RAD model is _________',
                'options': ['It requires highly skilled developers/designers.', 'It necessitates customer feedbacks.', 'It increases the component reusability.', 'Both (a) & (c)'],
                'answer': 'Both (a) & (c)'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Model selection is based on __________.',
                'options': ['Requirements', 'Development team & users', 'Project type & associated risk', 'all'],
                'answer': 'all'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following models does not necessitate defining requirements at the earliest in the lifecycle?',
                'options': ['RAD & Waterfall', 'Prototyping & Waterfall', 'Spiral & Prototyping', 'Spiral & RAD'],
                'answer': 'Spiral & Prototyping'
            },
            {
                'question': '_________ is identified as fourth generation langua',
                'options': ['Unix shell', 'C++', 'COBOL', 'FORTRAN'],

                'answer': 'Unix shell'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'COMPUTER ORGANIZATION',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': ' ___________ symbol is used to signify write back mode.',
                        'options': ['#', '^', '&', '!'],
                        'answer': '!'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The instructions which are used to load or store multiple operands are called as __________',
                'options': ['Banked instructions', 'Lump transfer instructions', 'Block transfer instructions', 'DMA instructions'],
                'answer': 'Block transfer instructions'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The instruction, MLA R0,R1,R2,R3 performs ______',
                'options': ['R0<-[R1]+[R2]+[R3]', 'R3<-[R0]+[R1]+[R2]', 'R0<-[R1]*[R2]+[R3]', 'R3<-[R0]*[R1]+[R2]'],
                'answer': 'R0<-[R1]*[R2]+[R3]'
            },
            {
                'question': '_________ instruction is used to get the 1’s complement of the operand.',
                'options': ['COMP', 'BIC', '~CMP', 'MVN'],
                'answer': 'MVN'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The offset used in the conditional branching is __________ bit.',
                'options': ['24', '32', '16', '8'],
                'answer': '24'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the two instructions sets the condition flag upon execution? ADDS R0,R1,R2,ADD R0,R1,R2',
                'options': [' i', 'ii', 'Both i and ii', 'nsufficient data'],
                'answer': 'i'
            },
            {
                'question': ' __________ directive is used to indicate the beginning of the program instruction or data.',
                'options': [' EQU', 'START', 'AREA', 'SPACE'],
                'answer': 'AREA'
            },
            {
                'question': '___________ directive specifies the start of the execution.',
                'options': ['START', 'ENTRY', 'MAIN', 'ORIGIN'],
                'answer': ' ENTRY'
            },
            {
                'question': ' ___________ directives are used to initialize operands.',
                'options': ['INT', 'DATAWORD', 'RESERVE', 'DCD'],
                'answer': 'DCD'
            },
            {
                'question': ' The pseudo instruction used to load an address into the register is _________',
                'options': ['LOAD', ' ADR', 'ASSIGN', 'PSLOAD'],
                'answer': ' ADR'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MICROPROCESSING AND INTERFACING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Microprocessor consists of?',
                        'options': [' ALU', 'register array', ' control unit', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': ' A machine language instruction format consists of -',
                'options': ['Operation code field & operand field', ' Operation code field', 'Operand field', 'none'],
                'answer': 'Operation code field & operand field'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The __________ controls the flow of data and instructions within the computer.',
                'options': ['control unit', ' register array', ' accumulator', ' ALU'],
                'answer': ' control unit'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a features of a Microprocessor?',
                'options': ['Versatility', 'Reliability', ' Low Bandwidth', 'Low Power Consumption'],
                'answer': 'Low Bandwidth'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The microprocessor ___________ those instructions from the memory',
                'options': [' Fetch', '. Decode', 'Execute', 'Execute'],
                'answer': ' Fetch'
            },
            {
                'question': 'It determines the number of operations per second?',
                'options': ['Bandwidth', 'Word Length', 'Clock Speed', 'Operations Speed'],
                'answer': 'Clock Speed'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Clock Speed is also known as?',
                'options': ['Clock Rate.', '. Clock Length.', 'Clock Set.', 'Clock Type.'],
                'answer': 'Clock Rate.'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An 8-bit microprocessor can process _____ data at a time',
                'options': [' 4-bit', '8-bit', '16-bit', 'none'],
                'answer': '8-bit'
            },
            {
                'question': '16-bit',
                'options': [' Instruction Set', ' Bandwidth', 'Bandspeed', 'Instruction Speed'],
                'answer': 'Bandwidth'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is false about microprocessor?',
                'options': ['he microprocessor is of small size chip, hence is not portable.', ' microprocessor chips are available at low prices', 'microprocessors are versatile', 'none'],
                'answer': ' The microprocessor is of small size chip, hence is not portable.'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'OBJECT ORIENTED PROGRAMMING USING JAVA',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?',
                        'options': ['Bytecode is executed by JVM', 'he applet makes the Java code secure and portable', 'Use of exception handling', 'Dynamic binding between objects'],
                        'answer': 'Bytecode is executed by JVM'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a Java features?',
                'options': ['Dynamic', 'Architecture Neutral', 'Use of pointers', 'Object-oriented'],
                'answer': 'Use of pointers'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The \u0021 article referred to as a',
                'options': ['Unicode escape sequence', 'Octal escape', 'Hexadecimal', 'Line feed'],
                'answer': 'Unicode escape sequence'
            },
            {
                'question': '__ is used to find and fix bugs in the Java programs.',
                'options': ['JVM', 'JRE', 'JDK', 'JDB'],
                'answer': 'JDB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following is a valid declaration of a char?',
                'options': ['char ch = \'utea\';', 'char ca = \'tea\';', 'char cr = u0223;', 'char cc = \'itea\';'],
                'answer': 'char ch = \'utea\';'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the return type of the hashCode() method in the Object class?',
                'options': ['Object', 'int', 'long', 'void'],
                'answer': 'int'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a valid long literal?',
                'options': ['ABH8097', 'L990023', '904423', '0xnf029L'],
                'answer': '0xnf029L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does the expression float a = 35 / 0 return?',
                'options': ['0', 'not anumber', 'infinity', 'runtime'],
                'answer': 'infinity'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which package contains the Random class?',
                'options': ['java.util package', 'java.lang package', 'java.awt package', 'java.io package'],
                'answer': 'java.util package'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An interface with no fields or methods is known as a _____',
                'options': ['Runnable Interface', 'Marker Interface', 'Abstract Interface', 'CharSequence Interface'],
                'answer': 'Marker Interface'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'FORMAL LANGUAGES AND AUTOMATA THEORY',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': ' Which of the following is an utility of state elimination phenomenon?',
                        'options': ['DFA to NFA', 'NFA to DFA', 'DFA to Regular Expression', 'all'],
                        'answer': 'DFA to Regular Expression'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If we have more than one accepting states or an accepting state with an outdegree, which of the following actions will be taken?',
                'options': ['addition of new state', 'removal of a state', 'make the newly added state as final', 'more than one option is correct'],
                'answer': 'more than one option is correct'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following methods is suitable for conversion of DFA to RE?',
                'options': ['Brzozowski method', 'Arden’s method', 'Walter’s method', 'all'],
                'answer': 'Brzozowski method'
            },
            {
                'question': ' The behaviour of NFA can be simulated using DFA.',
                'options': ['always', ' never', 'sometimes', 'none of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'always'
            },
            {
                'question': 't is suitable to use ____________ method/methods to convert a DFA to regular expression.',
                'options': ['Brzozowski method', 'Transitive Closure properties', 'State elimination method', 'All of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'All of the mentioned'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Is it possible to obtain more than one regular expression from a given DFA using the state elimination method?',
                'options': ['yes', 'no', 'both yes and no', 'none'],
                'answer': 'yes'
            },
            {
                'question': 'For every removed state, there is a regular expression produced.',
                'options': ['true', 'false', 'both true and false', 'none'],
                'answer': 'true'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Finite state machine is ---tuple machine',
                'options': ['4', '5', '6', 'unlimited'],
                'answer': '5'
            },
            {
                'question': 'No.of states required to accept string ends with 101',
                'options': ['3', '4', '2', '8'],
                'answer': '4'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Finite automata needs minimum ---number of stacks.',
                'options': ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
                'answer': '0'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MICROPROCESSING AND INTERFACING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Microprocessor consists of?',
                        'options': [' ALU', 'register array', ' control unit', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': ' A machine language instruction format consists of -',
                'options': ['Operation code field & operand field', ' Operation code field', 'Operand field', 'none'],
                'answer': 'Operation code field & operand field'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The __________ controls the flow of data and instructions within the computer.',
                'options': ['control unit', ' register array', ' accumulator', ' ALU'],
                'answer': ' control unit'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a features of a Microprocessor?',
                'options': ['Versatility', 'Reliability', ' Low Bandwidth', 'Low Power Consumption'],
                'answer': 'Low Bandwidth'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The microprocessor ___________ those instructions from the memory',
                'options': [' Fetch', '. Decode', 'Execute', 'Execute'],
                'answer': ' Fetch'
            },
            {
                'question': 'It determines the number of operations per second?',
                'options': ['Bandwidth', 'Word Length', 'Clock Speed', 'Operations Speed'],
                'answer': 'Clock Speed'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Clock Speed is also known as?',
                'options': ['Clock Rate.', '. Clock Length.', 'Clock Set.', 'Clock Type.'],
                'answer': 'Clock Rate.'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An 8-bit microprocessor can process _____ data at a time',
                'options': [' 4-bit', '8-bit', '16-bit', 'none'],
                'answer': '8-bit'
            },
            {
                'question': '16-bit',
                'options': [' Instruction Set', ' Bandwidth', 'Bandspeed', 'Instruction Speed'],
                'answer': 'Bandwidth'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is false about microprocessor?',
                'options': ['he microprocessor is of small size chip, hence is not portable.', ' microprocessor chips are available at low prices', 'microprocessors are versatile', 'none'],
                'answer': ' The microprocessor is of small size chip, hence is not portable.'
            },
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'JAVA PROGRAMMING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?',
                        'options': ['Bytecode is executed by JVM', 'he applet makes the Java code secure and portable', 'Use of exception handling', 'Dynamic binding between objects'],
                        'answer': 'Bytecode is executed by JVM'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a Java features?',
                'options': ['Dynamic', 'Architecture Neutral', 'Use of pointers', 'Object-oriented'],
                'answer': 'Use of pointers'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The \u0021 article referred to as a',
                'options': ['Unicode escape sequence', 'Octal escape', 'Hexadecimal', 'Line feed'],
                'answer': 'Unicode escape sequence'
            },
            {
                'question': '__ is used to find and fix bugs in the Java programs.',
                'options': ['JVM', 'JRE', 'JDK', 'JDB'],
                'answer': 'JDB'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following is a valid declaration of a char?',
                'options': ['char ch =  \'utea\';', 'char ca = \'tea\';', 'char cr = u0223;', 'char cc = \'itea\';'],
                'answer': 'char ch = \'utea'

            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the return type of the hashCode() method in the Object class?',
                'options': ['Object', 'int', 'long', 'void'],
                'answer': 'int'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a valid long literal?',
                'options': ['ABH8097', 'L990023', '904423', '0xnf029L'],
                'answer': '0xnf029L'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does the expression float a = 35 / 0 return?',
                'options': ['0', 'not anumber', 'infinity', 'runtime'],
                'answer': 'infinity'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which package contains the Random class?',
                'options': ['java.util package', 'java.lang package', 'java.awt package', 'java.io package'],
                'answer': 'java.util package'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An interface with no fields or methods is known as a _____',
                'options': ['Runnable Interface', 'Marker Interface', 'Abstract Interface', 'CharSequence Interface'],
                'answer': 'Marker Interface'
            },
        ]
    }
]
sem_5 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'OPERATING SYSTEMS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'which of the following is not an operting system ?',
                        'options': ['Windows', 'Linux', 'Oracle', 'Dos'],
                        'answer': 'Oracle'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the maximum lenght of the filename in DOS?',
                'options': ['4', '5', '8', '12'],
                'answer': '8'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is the extension of notepad?',
                'options': ['.txt', '.xls', '.ppt', '.bump'],
                'answer': '.txt'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What else is a command interpreter called?',
                'options': ['prompt', 'kernel ', 'shell', 'command'],
                'answer': 'shell'
            },

            {
                'question': 'What is the full name of FAT ?',
                'options': ['File attribute table', 'File allocation table', 'Font attribute table', 'format allocation table'],
                'answer': 'File allocation table'
            },

            {
                'question': 'What is the mean of the Booting in the operating system ?',
                'options': ['Restarting computer', 'Install the program', 'To scan', 'To turn off'],
                'answer': 'File allocation table'
            },
            {
                'question': 'When the page fault occur ?',
                'options': ['The page present in memory', 'The deadlock occurs', 'The page does not present in memory', 'The buffering occurs'],
                'answer': 'The page doest not present in memory'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which is the Linux operating system?',
                'options': ['Private operating system', 'Windows operating system', 'Open-source operating system', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Open source operating system'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the full name of the IDL?',
                'options': ['Interface definition language', 'Interface direct language', 'Interface data library', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Interface definition language'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If the page size increases, the internal fragmentation is also?',
                'options': ['Decreases', 'Increases', 'Remains constant', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Increases'
            }


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'COMPUTER NETWORKS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of these is a standard interface for serial data transmission??',
                        'options': ['system Design', 'coding', 'system Testing', 'preliminary Investigation and Analysis'],
                        'answer': 'preliminary Investigation and Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does the study of an existing system refer to?',
                'options': ['Details of DFD', 'Feasibility Study', 'System Analysis', 'System Planning'],
                'answer': 'System Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What does RAD stand for?',
                'options': ['Rapid Application Document', 'Rapid Application Development', 'Relative Application Development', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Rapid Application Development'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The system by which companies are managed and controlled is known as?',
                'options': ['Management', 'Strategic ', 'Corporate', '.Internal'],
                'answer': 'Corporate'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Human Resource Management is ?',
                'options': ['Employee oriented', 'Employer oriented', 'Legally oriented', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Employer oriented'
            },

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'COMPUTER NETWORK',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'what is the first step in the software development lifecycle ?',
                        'options': ['ASCII', 'RS232C', '2', 'Centronics'],
                        'answer': 'RS23c'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following transmission directions listed is not a legitimate channel?',
                'options': ['Simplex', 'Half Duplex', 'Full Duplex', 'Double Duplex'],
                'answer':  ' Double Duplex'
            },
            {

                'question': '"Parity bits" are used for which of the following purposes?',
                'options': ['Encryption of data', 'To transmit faster', 'To detect errors', 'To identify the user'],
                'answer': 'To detect errors'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The location of a resource on the internet is given by its?',
                'options': ['Protocol', ' URL', 'E-mail address', 'ICQ'],
                'answer': 'URL'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The term HTTP stands for ?',
                'options': ['Hyper terminal tracing program', 'Hypertext tracing protocol', 'Hypertext transfer protocol', 'Hypertext transfer program'],
                'answer': 'Hypertext transfer protocol'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A proxy server is used as the computer?',
                'options': ['with external access', 'acting as a backup', 'performing file handling', 'accessing user permissions'],
                'answer': 'with exterter access'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which one of the following would breach the integrity of a system?',
                'options': ['Looking the room to prevent theft', 'Full access rights for all users', 'Fitting the system with an anti-theft device', 'Protecting the device against willful or accidental damage'],
                'answer': ' Full access rights for all users'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which software prevents the external access to a system?',
                'options': ['Firewall', 'Gateway', 'Router', 'Virus checker'],
                'answer': ' Firewall'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following best describes uploading information?',
                'options': ['Sorting data on a disk drive', 'Sending information to a host computer', 'Receiving information from a host computer', 'Sorting data on a hard drive'],
                'answer': 'Sending information to a host computer'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which one of the following is the most common internet protocol?',
                'options': ['HTML', 'NetBEUI', 'TCP/IP', 'IPX/SPX'],
                'answer': ' TCP/IP'
            },


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'OBJECT ORIENTED ANALYSIS & DESIGN',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'A  is an abstraction of something for the purpose of understanding it before building it?',
                        'options': ['Mock-up', 'Model', 'Prototype', 'All the above'],
                        'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Object-Oriented Modelling allows?',
                'options': ['Higher productivity', 'lower maintenance cost', 'better quality can be achieved', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Object Oriented Modeling for building systems takes the as the basis.?',
                'options': ['Class', 'Object', 'Model', 'Modules'],
                'answer': 'Object'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The object model describes the  of a system?',
                'options': ['static', 'structural ', 'data aspects', 'Static, structural, and data aspects'],
                'answer': 'Corporate'
            },

            {
                'question': 'A link is a physicalbor conceptual connection between ?',
                'options': ['Objects', 'Object instances', 'Classes', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'Object instances'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An association maybe ?',
                'options': ['unary', 'binary', 'ternary or n-ary', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'unary'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The attribute(s) is/are associated with the association is called ?',
                'options': ['Link attribute', 'Derived attribute', 'Multi-valued attribute', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Link attribute'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a name that uniquely identifies one end of an association?',
                'options': ['Label name of the link', 'Role name', 'Link attribute name', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Role name'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A qualifier is an that reduces the effective multiplicity of an association.?',
                'options': ['Association attribute', 'Attribute', 'Special attribute', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Special attribute'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Inheritance is a  relationship between two classes.?',
                'options': ['“is-a”', 'Part of', 'Both a and b', 'None'],
                'answer': '"is-a"'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Generalization is reverse of ?',
                'options': ['Aggregation', 'Inheritance', 'Specialization', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Specialization'
            },

        ]
    },







    {
        'subject_name': 'PRINCIPLES OF PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'In high level programming language Pascal, each program statement ends with the?',
                        'options': ['comma ', 'semicolon ', 'double quotation marks', ' single quotation marks'],
                        'answer': 'Semicolon'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Type of program which can be run on different types of computer by making little changes into it is classified as ?',
                'options': ['Portable program', ' fixed program', 'standard program ', 'compiled program '],
                'answer': 'Portable program'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In unstructured programming language BASIC, program can be divided into the ?',
                'options': ['different modules', 'different arrays', 'different dimensions', 'different procedures'],
                'answer': 'different procedures'
            },
            {
                'question': 'When there is range of numbers involved in a program, it can be stored as?',
                'options': ['real numbers', 'original numbers ', 'rational numbers', 'irrational numbers'],
                'answer': 'real number'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Technique of using fixed words for machine code functions is classified as  ?',
                'options': ['Mnemonics  ', 'Mechanics', 'compiler', 'translator '],
                'answer': 'Mnemonics'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not true of FORTRAN?',
                'options': ['was developed for scientific and mathematical applications ', 'is one of the oldest high-level languages ', 'is a problem oriented language', 'requires extensive internal documentation'],
                'answer': ' is one of the oldest high-level languages '
            },
            {
                'question': 'Main type of functions does not includes  ?',
                'options': ['built-in function  ', 'top down procedures', 'programmer defined functio', 'user-defined function '],
                'answer': 'top down procedures'
            },
            {
                'question': ' In programming language COBOL, symbol of "//" is used instead of  ?',
                'options': ['unmarked variable   ', 'unmarked strings ', 'remarks', 'marked structure  '],
                'answer': 'remarks'
            },
            {
                'question': ' program used for interactive computing is ?',
                'options': ['translator', 'executor ', ' instructor', ' interpreter'],
                'answer': 'interpreter'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In programming language BASIC, area is calculated as ?',
                'options': ['0 Area=Width*Length ', ' 100 Area : = Width*Length  ', ' area : = Width*Length ', ' area 100 : length*width'],
                'answer': '0 Area=width*Lenght'
            },

            {
                'question': 'In programming a single instruction is classified as ?',
                'options': ['set of instructions ', ' statement  ', 'set of code', ' set of formula'],
                'answer': 'statement'
            }




        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'SOFTWARE TESTING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'What is Integration Testing?',
                        'options': ['SDLC Model', 'Test Type', ' Test Design Technique', ' Test Level'],
                        'answer': 'Test Level'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Cyclomatic number theory in a graph is defined by.?',

                'options': [' e – n + 2', ' e – n + 1', ' e – n – 2', 'e – n – 1'],
                'answer': 'e - n + 1'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following is/are true regarding Catastrophic Defects?',
                'options': [' Hide other defects.', ' Invokes other defects.', ' Failure of the software and data can be recovered.', ' Application crashes and data cannot be recovered.'],
                'answer': 'Application crashes and data cannot be recovered'
            },
            {
                'question': 'White Box Techniques are also called as?',
                'options': [' Structural Testing', 'Design-Based Testing ', 'Error Guessing Technique', 'Experience-Based Technique'],
                'answer': 'Structural Testing'
            },

            {
                'question': ' Incidents would not be raised against ?',
                'options': ['requirements', ' documentation', 'test cases', 'improvements suggested by users'],
                'answer': 'improvement suggested by users'
            },
            {
                'question': '  Maintenance testing is performed using which methodology ?',
                'options': [' Retesting', ' Sanity testing', ' Breadth test and depth test', 'Confirmation testing'],
                'answer': 'Breadth test and depth test'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The order in which Test Levels are performed is ?',
                'options': [' Unit, Integration, Acceptance, System', ' Unit, System, Integration, Acceptance', 'Unit, Integration, System, Acceptance', 'It depends on the nature of a project'],
                'answer': 'It depends on the nature of a project'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which Test Document describes the Exit Criteria of Testing ?',
                'options': ['  Test Case', '  Test Plan', '  Test Summary Report', 'Defect Report'],
                'answer': 'Test plan'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is Decision Testing?',
                'options': ['Black Box Test Design Technique', ' White Box Test Design Technique', ' Gray Box Test Design Technique', ' Experience-based Test Design Technique'],
                'answer': 'White Box Test Design Technique'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is Exploratory Testing ?',
                'options': ['  Black Box Test Design Technique', '  White Box Test Design Technique', ' Gray Box Test Design Technique', ' Experience-based Test Design Technique'],
                'answer': 'Experience-based Test Design Technique'
            },
            {
                'question': ' What is Fault Masking? ?',
                'options': ['Creating a test case that does not reveal a fault', 'Error condition hiding another error condition', 'Masking a fault by the developer', 'Masking a fault by a tester'],
                'answer': 'Error condition hiding another error condition'
            }


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'INTRODUCTION TO BIG DATA',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Data in ___________ bytes size is called Big Data.?',
                        'options': [' Tera', 'Giga', ' Peta', ' Meta'],
                        'answer': 'Peta'
            },
            {
                'question': 'How many V s of Big Data?',
                'options': ['2', '3', '4', '5'],
                'answer': '5'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Transaction data of the bank is?',
                'options': ['structured data', ' unstructured data', ' Both A and B', ' None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Structured data'
            },
            {
                'question': ' In how many forms BigData could be found?',
                'options': ['2', '3', '4', '5'],
                'answer': '3'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which of the following are Benefits of Big Data Processing ?',
                'options': [' Businesses can utilize outside intelligence while taking decisions', ' Improved customer service', 'Better operational efficiency', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following are incorrect Big Data Technologies?',
                'options': [' Apache Hadoop', ' Apache Spark', '  Apache Kafka', '  Apache Pytarch'],
                'answer': 'Apache Pytarch'
            },
            {
                'question': ' The overall percentage of the world’s total data has been created just within the past two years is ?',
                'options': [' 80%', ' 85%', '  90%', ' 95%'],
                'answer': '90%'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Apache Kafka is an open-source platform that was created by ?',
                'options': ['LinkedIn', ' Facebook', '  Google', ' IBM'],
                'answer': 'LinkedIn'
            },
            {
                'question': ' What was Hadoop named after? ?',
                'options': ['Creator Doug Cutting’s favorite circus act', '  Cuttings high school rock band', '  The toy elephant of Cutting’s son', '  A sound Cutting’s laptop made during Hadoop development'],
                'answer': 'The toy elephant of Cutting’s son'
            },
            {
                'question': ' What are the main components of Big Data ?',
                'options': [' MapReduce', '  HDFS', '   YARN', '  All of the above'],
                'answer': ' All of the above'
            }



        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'OBJECT ORIENTED ANALYSIS AND DESIGN  AND SOFTWARE TESTING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Combination of single, multiple, hierarchical, and multilevel inheritance forms?',
                        'options': ['Hierarchical Inheritance', 'Hybrid inheritance', 'Containership', ' None'],
                        'answer': 'Hybrid inheritance'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following models depicts states, transitions, events, and actions?',
                'options': ['Functional model', 'Dynamic model', 'Object model', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Dynamic model'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following models includes event trace diagrams describing scenarios?',
                'options': ['Dynamic model', 'object model', 'Functional model', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'Rapid Application Development'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A/An ———  is a one-way transmission of information from one object to another?',
                'options': ['Message', 'Event', 'Change of event', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Event'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The outcomes of dynamic modeling are —— ?',
                'options': ['scenario', 'event-trace diagram', 'State diagram', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'the testing have been stopped when?',
                'options': ['the faults have been fixed', 'all the tests run', 'the time completed', 'the risk are revolved'],
                'answer': 'the risk are revolved'
            },
            {
                'question': '_________ is not Structural testing?',
                'options': ['Parallel', 'Acceptance', 'Stress', 'Regression'],
                'answer': 'Acceptance'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Testing comes under_________ category of cost of quality?',
                'options': ['Appraisal', 'Failure', 'Preventive', 'None of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'Appraisal'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Testing which performed first is?',
                'options': ['Dynamic testing', 'Black box testing', 'White box testing', 'static testing'],
                'answer': 'Static testing'
            },
            {
                'question': '_________ testing focuses on heavily testing of one particular module?',
                'options': ['Gorilla Testing', 'Fuzz Testing', 'Inter-System Testing', 'Breadth Testing'],
                'answer': 'Gorilla Testing'
            }


        ]
    },

    {
        'subject_name': 'OPERTING SYSTEMS LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The Operating System was first introduced, the primary goal was mainly to ___?',
                        'options': [' Share memory', ' Share memory', 'Optimize resources', ' None of the given'],
                        'answer': 'Optimize resources'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Operating System should work in a network as well as ___ environment.?',
                'options': [' diverted', 'data', 'distributed', ' direct'],
                'answer': 'distributed'
            },
            {
                'question': '_____ may be the first elementary Operating System.?',
                'options': ['Resident System', 'Resident Monitor', 'Resident Monitor', 'Resident Computer'],
                'answer': 'Resident Monitor'
            },
            {
                'question': '____ is an example of single user Operating System.?',
                'options': ['Ms-Dos', ' Linux', 'Unix', ' Basic'],
                'answer': 'Ms-Dos'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The ___ program is not allowed to read data from the disk.?',
                'options': ['OS', 'Application', ' System', ' Resident Monitor'],
                'answer': 'Application'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following is not an operating system?',
                'options': ['Windows', 'Linux', 'Oracle', 'DOS'],
                'answer': 'Oracle'
            },
            {
                'question': ' BIOS is used?',
                'options': ['By operating system', 'By compiler', 'By interpreter', 'By application software'],
                'answer': 'By operating system'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Bankers algorithm is used?',
                'options': ['To prevent deadlock', 'To deadlock recovery', 'To solve the deadlock', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'To prevent deadlock'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the fence register used fo?',
                'options': ['To disk protection', 'To CPU protection', 'To memory protection', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'To memory protection'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Who provides the interface to access the services of the operating system?',
                'options': ['API', 'System call', 'Library', 'Assembly instruction'],
                'answer': 'System call'
            },


        ]
    },
]
sem_6 = [
    {
        'Subject_name': 'COMPILER DESIGN',
        'QUESTION': [
            {

                'question': 'Which table is a permanent database that has an entry for each terminal symbol?',
                'options': ['Reductions', ' Identifier table', 'Literal table', 'Terminal table'],
                'answer': 'Terminal Table'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The action of parsing the source program into proper syntactic classes is called?',
                'options': ['General syntax analysis', 'Interpretation analysis', ' Syntax analysis', ' Lexical analysis'],
                'answer': 'Lexical analysis'
            },

            {
                'question': ' bottom-up parser generates?',
                'options': [' Left-most derivation in reverse', 'Left-most derivation', ' Right-most derivation in reverse', ' Right –most derivation'],
                'answer': ' Right-most derivation in reverse'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The bottom-up parsing method is also called?',
                'options': ['Shift reduce parsing', 'Predictive parsing ', 'Recursive descent parsing', ' None of these'],
                'answer': 'Shift reduce parsing'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The method which merges the bodies of two loops is ?',
                'options': [' Constant folding', ' Loop jamming', ' Loop unrolling', ' None of these'],
                'answer': 'Loop jamming'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Compiler translates the source code to?',
                'options': ['  Executable code', ' Machine code', '  Binary code', ' Both B and C'],
                'answer': 'Both B and C'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following groups is/are token together into sematic structure?',
                'options': ['Syntax analyzer', '  Intermediate code generation', '  Lexical analyzer ', ' Semantic analyzer'],
                'answer': 'Lexical analyzer'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Compiler should report the presence of __________ in the source program, in translation process.?',
                'options': [' Classes', ' Objects', ' Errors', ' Text'],
                'answer': 'Errors'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the output of lexical analyzer?',
                'options': ['  A parse tree', '  A list of tokens', ' Intermediate code', ' Machine code'],
                'answer': 'A list of tokens'
            },
            {
                'question': 'How many parts of compiler are there?',
                'options': ['  1', '  2', ' 4', ' 8'],
                'answer': '2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Grammar of the programming is checked at _______ phase of compiler?',
                'options': ['Semantic analysis ', '  syntax analysis', ' Code optimization ', 'code generation'],
                'answer': 'Syntax analysis'
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA WAREHOUSE AND MINING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Data dictionary ?',
                        'options': ['A large collection of data mostly stored in a computer system', 'The removal of noise errors and  incorrect input from a database', 'The sytematic description of systematic structure of a specfic database.It describe the structure of attribute the tables and foreign key relationships', 'None of these'],
                        'answer': 'The sytematic description of systematic structure of a specfic database.It describe the structure of attribute the tables and foreign key relationships'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data warehouse is ?',
                'options': ['The actual discovery phase of a knowledge discovery process', 'The stage of selecting the right data for a KDD process', 'A subject-oriented integrated time-variant non-volatile collection of data in support of management', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'A subject-oriented integrated time-variant non-volatile collection of data in support of management'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data cleaning?',
                'options': ['Large collection of data mostly stored in a computer system', 'The removed of noise errors and incorrect input from a database', 'The systematic description of the syntactics structure of a specific database.It describe the structure of the attribute the tables and foreign key relationships', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'The removed of noise errors and incorrect input from a database'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data srubbing is which of the following?',
                'options': ['A process to reject data from the data warehouse and to create the necessary indexes', 'A process to load the data in the data warehouse and to create the necessary indexes ', 'A process to upgrade the quality of data after it is moved into a data warehouse', 'A process to upgrade the quality of data before it is moved into a data warehouse'],
                'answer': 'A process to upgrade the quality of data before it is moved into a data warehouse'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The @active data warehouse architecture includes which of the following?',
                'options': ['At least one data mart', 'Data that can extracted from numerous internal and external sources', 'Near real-time updates', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An operational system is which of the following?',
                'options': ['A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on historical data', ' A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on current data', 'A system that is used to support decision making and is based on current data', 'A system that is used to support decision making and is based on historical data'],
                'answer': ' A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on current data '
            },
            {
                'question': 'A data warehouse is which of the following?',
                'options': ['Can be updated by end users', 'Contain numerous naming conventional and formats', 'Organized around important subject areas', 'Contains only current data'],
                'answer': 'Organized around important subject areas'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A snowflake schema is which of the following types of tables?',
                'options': ['Fact', 'Dimension', 'Helper', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The generic two-level data warehouse architecture include which of the following?',
                'options': ['At least one data mart', 'Data that extracted from numerous internal and external sources', 'Near real-time updates', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'Data that extracted from numerous internal and external sources'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Fact tables are which of the following?',
                'options': ['Completely denoralized', 'Partially denoralized', 'Completely normalized', 'Party normalized'],
                'answer': 'Completely normalized'
            }



        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DESIGN PATTERNS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': ' Which of the following is correct about Factory design pattern. ?',
                        'options': ['This type of design pattern comes under creating pattern', 'Factory pattern creates object without exposing the current logic to the client', 'Factory pattern refers to newly created object using a common interface', '  All the above'],
                        'answer': 'preliminary investigation and Analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following pattern works as a bridge between two incompatible interfaces?',
                'options': ['Builder pattern', 'Adapter pattern', 'Prototype Pattern', 'Filter Pattern'],
                'answer': 'Adapter pattern'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which of the following pattern provides a way to evaluate language grammar or expression?',
                'options': ['Proxy Pattern', 'Chain of Responsibility Pattern', 'Command Pattern', 'Interpreter pattern'],
                'answer': 'Interpreter pattern'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following pattern a request is wrapped under an object as command and passed to invoker object?',
                'options': ['Proxy Pattern', 'Chain of Responsibility Pattern ', 'Command Pattern', 'Interpreter pattern'],
                'answer': 'Command Pattern'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which of the following describes the Business Delegate pattern correctly ?',
                'options': ['In this pattern, a visitor class is used which changes the executing algorthim of an element class', 'This pattern is used to separate applications concerns', 'This pattern is used to decouple presentation their and business tier', 'This pattern is used in EJB persistance mechnanism.'],
                'answer': 'This pattern is used to separate applications concerns'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following pattern is used to provide a centralized request handling mechanism so that all requests will be handled by a single handler?',
                'options': ['DAO Pattern', 'Front Controller Pattern ', 'Intercepting Pattern', 'Service Locator Pattern'],
                'answer': 'Service Locator Pattern'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Which type of design patterns provide a way to create objects while hiding the creation logic, rather than instantiating objects directly using new opreator ?',
                'options': ['Creational Design Patterns', 'Structural Design Patterns ', 'Behavioral Design Pattern', 'JSEE Design Patterns'],
                'answer': 'Creational Design Patterns'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is the correct list of entities of Business Delegate pattern ?',
                'options': ['Business Delegated, LookUp Service,Business Service ', 'Client, Business Delegation,LookUp Service,Business Service', 'Client,LookUp Service,Business service', 'Client, Bussiness Delegated, Business Service'],
                'answer': 'Client, Business Delegation,LookUp Service,Business Service'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which  design pattern works on data and  action taken baed on data provided ?',
                'options': ['Command pattern', 'Singleton pattern', 'MVC pattern', 'Facade pattern'],
                'answer': 'Command pattern'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which design pattern defines one-to-many dependency among objects?',
                'options': ['Singleton pattern', 'Facade pattern', 'Observer pattern', 'Factory method pattern'],
                'answer': 'Observer pattern'
            }



        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DESIGN AND ANALYSIS OF ALGORITHM',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Steps of Divide and Conquer approach Select one ?',
                        'options': ['Divide, Conquer and Combine Correct', 'Divide, Conquer and Combine Correct', 'Combine, Divide and Conquer', 'Divide combine and conquer'],
                        'answer': 'Divide, Conquer and Combine Correct'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The complexity of searching an element from a set of n elements using Binary search algorithm is ?',
                'options': ['0(n log n)', '0(log n)', '0(n2)', '0(n)'],
                'answer': '0(log n)'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In the development of dynamic programming the value of an optimal solution is computed in Select one?',
                'options': [' Top up fashion', 'Bottom up fashion ', 'In any way', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Bottom up fashion '
            },
            {
                'question': 'The number of operations in Matrix multiplications M1, M2, M3, M4 and M5 of sizes 5X10, 10X100, 100X2, 2X20 and 20X50 ?',
                'options': ['5830', '4600 correct ', '6900', '.12800'],
                'answer': '4600'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which case of Master’s theorem is applicable in the recurrence relation T(n)=0.5*T(n/2)+1/n? ?',
                'options': ['. Case 3', 'Case 2', 'Mathers theorem is not applicable ', 'Case 2'],
                'answer': 'Mathers theorem is not applicable '
            },
            {
                'question': '______ is a condition that is always true at a particular point in an algorithm. ?',
                'options': ['assertion', 'constant', 'exeception', 'invariant '],
                'answer': 'invariant'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Division pattern of problem  in divide and conquer approach ?',
                'options': ['iterative', 'recursive ', 'Parallel', 'Random'],
                'answer': 'recursive'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The running time of quick sort depends on the selection of ?',
                'options': ['Select of pivot elements ', 'Number of inputs', 'Number of passes', 'Arrangements of the elements'],
                'answer': 'Select of pivot elements'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following sorting algorithm does not have a worst case running ?',
                'options': ['Quick sort ', 'Merge sort', 'Insertion Sort', 'Bubble sort Incorrect'],
                'answer': 'Merge sort'
            },
            {
                'question': '.Run Time of Merge Sort is ?',
                'options': ['BIG 0 of N log N incorrect ', 'Gamma of n log N', 'Theta of N log N', 'Omega of N log N'],
                'answer': 'Theta of N log N'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'WEB AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGY',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'From which tag the descriptive list starts ?',
                        'options': ['<LL>', ' <DD>', '<DL>', ' <DS>'],
                        'answer': '<DL>'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The elements and have the following characteristics?',
                'options': [' Element inherits properties defined for in a stylesheet', 'And have no real meanings as html tags unless stylesheet is applied', 'Elements and define content to be inline or block-level', 'And are used as alternatives for the element'],
                'answer': 'Elements and define content to be inline or block-level'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The latest HTML standard is?',
                'options': [' XML', 'SGML', ' HTML 4.0', ' HTML 5.0'],
                'answer': ' HTML 5.0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'HTML stands for?',
                'options': [' Hyper Text Markup Language', ' High Text Markup Language', 'Hyper Tabular Markup Language', ' None of these'],
                'answer': 'Hyper Text Markup Language'
            },

            {
                'question': ' The function returns a Boolean value that indicates whether a specified expression can be evaluated as a number; in ASP is ?',
                'options': [' IsNumeric()', ' IsNumber()', ' IsNotNumeric()', ' IsNotNumber()'],
                'answer': ' IsNumeric()'
            },
            {
                'question': 'HTML is a subset of?',
                'options': ['  SGMT', ' SGML', 'SGMD', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'SGML'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Any part of the graphic that is not included in another hot zone is considered to be part of ?',
                'options': ['   Rect', ' Point', 'Default', 'Polygon'],
                'answer': 'Default'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The body tag usually used after ?',
                'options': [' Title tag', ' HEAD tag', 'EM tag', 'Form tag'],
                'answer': 'HEAD tag'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following tag is used to mark a beginning of paragraph?',
                'options': [' <TD>', ' <br>', ' <P>', ' <TR>'],
                'answer': '<p>'
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'ARITIFICAL INTELLIGENCE',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Artifical Intelligence is about?',
                        'options': ['Playing a game on computer', 'Making a machine Intelligent', 'Programming on machine with your Own intelligence', 'Putting your intelligence in Machines'],
                        'answer': 'Making a machine Intelligent'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Who is know as the Father of AI ?',
                'options': ['Fisher Ada', 'Alan Turing', 'John McCarthy', 'Allen Newwll'],
                'answer': 'John McCarthy'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Select the most appropriate situation for that a blind search can be used ?',
                'options': ['Real-life situation', 'Small Search Space', 'Complex game', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'Small Search Space'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The application/applications of Artifical Intelligence is/are?',
                'options': ['Expert Systems', 'Gaming ', 'Vision System', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Among the given options, Which search algorithm requires less memory ?',
                'options': ['Optimal Search', 'Depth First Search', 'Breadth-First Search', 'Linear Search'],
                'answer': 'Depth First Search'
            },
            {
                'question': 'If a robot is able to change its own trajectory as per the external conditions, then the robot is considered as the ?',
                'options': ['Mobile', 'Non-Servo', 'Open Loop', 'Intelligent'],
                'answer': 'Intelligent'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the given language is not commonly used for AI?',
                'options': ['LISP', 'PROLOG', 'Python', 'Perl'],
                'answer': 'Perl'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The component of an Expert system is __________?',
                'options': ['knowledge Base', 'Inference Engine', 'User Interface', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The available ways to slove a problem of state-space-search?',
                'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4'],
                'answer': '2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An AI agent percevies and acts upon the environment using____?',
                'options': ['Sensors', 'Perceiver', 'Actuators', 'Both a and c'],
                'answer': 'Both a and c'
            }


        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'WEB AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGIES LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'From which tag the descriptive list starts ?',
                        'options': ['<LL>', ' <DD>', '<DL>', ' <DS>'],
                        'answer': '<DL>'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The elements and have the following characteristics?',
                'options': [' Element inherits properties defined for in a stylesheet', 'And have no real meanings as html tags unless stylesheet is applied', 'Elements and define content to be inline or block-level', 'And are used as alternatives for the element'],
                'answer': 'Elements and define content to be inline or block-level'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The latest HTML standard is?',
                'options': [' XML', 'SGML', ' HTML 4.0', ' HTML 5.0'],
                'answer': ' HTML 5.0'
            },
            {
                'question': 'HTML stands for?',
                'options': [' Hyper Text Markup Language', ' High Text Markup Language', 'Hyper Tabular Markup Language', ' None of these'],
                'answer': 'Hyper Text Markup Language'
            },

            {
                'question': ' The function returns a Boolean value that indicates whether a specified expression can be evaluated as a number; in ASP is ?',
                'options': [' IsNumeric()', ' IsNumber()', ' IsNotNumeric()', ' IsNotNumber()'],
                'answer': ' IsNumeric()'
            },
            {
                'question': 'HTML is a subset of?',
                'options': ['  SGMT', ' SGML', 'SGMD', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'SGML'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Any part of the graphic that is not included in another hot zone is considered to be part of ?',
                'options': ['   Rect', ' Point', 'Default', 'Polygon'],
                'answer': 'Default'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The body tag usually used after ?',
                'options': [' Title tag', ' HEAD tag', 'EM tag', 'Form tag'],
                'answer': 'HEAD tag'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following tag is used to mark a beginning of paragraph?',
                'options': [' <TD>', ' <br>', ' <P>', ' <TR>'],
                'answer': '<p>'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA WAREHOUSE AND MINING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {


                'question': 'Data dictionary ?',
                'options': ['A large collection of data mostly stored in a computer system', 'The removal of noise errors and  incorrect input from a database', 'The sytematic description of systematic structure of a specfic database.It describe the structure of attribute the tables and foreign key relationships', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'The sytematic description of systematic structure of a specfic database.It describe the structure of attribute the tables and foreign key relationships'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data warehouse is ?',
                'options': ['The actual discovery phase of a knowledge discovery process', 'The stage of selecting the right data for a KDD process', 'A subject-oriented integrated time-variant non-volatile collection of data in support of management', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'A subject-oriented integrated time-variant non-volatile collection of data in support of management'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data cleaning?',
                'options': ['Large collection of data mostly stored in a computer system', 'The removed of noise errors and incorrect input from a database', 'The systematic description of the syntactics structure of a specific database.It describe the structure of the attribute the tables and foreign key relationships', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'The removed of noise errors and incorrect input from a database'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Data srubbing is which of the following?',
                'options': ['A process to reject data from the data warehouse and to create the necessary indexes', 'A process to load the data in the data warehouse and to create the necessary indexes ', 'A process to upgrade the quality of data after it is moved into a data warehouse', 'A process to upgrade the quality of data before it is moved into a data warehouse'],
                'answer': 'A process to upgrade the quality of data before it is moved into a data warehouse'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The @active data warehouse architecture includes which of the following?',
                'options': ['At least one data mart', 'Data that can extracted from numerous internal and external sources', 'Near real-time updates', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'An operational system is which of the following?',
                'options': ['A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on historical data', ' A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on current data', 'A system that is used to support decision making and is based on current data', 'A system that is used to support decision making and is based on historical data'],
                'answer': ' A system that is used to run the business in real time and is based on current data '
            },
            {
                'question': 'A data warehouse is which of the following?',
                'options': ['Can be updated by end users', 'Contain numerous naming conventional and formats', 'Organized around important subject areas', 'Contains only current data'],
                'answer': 'Organized around important subject areas'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A snowflake schema is which of the following types of tables?',
                'options': ['Fact', 'Dimension', 'Helper', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The generic two-level data warehouse architecture include which of the following?',
                'options': ['At least one data mart', 'Data that extracted from numerous internal and external sources', 'Near real-time updates', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'Data that extracted from numerous internal and external sources'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Fact tables are which of the following?',
                'options': ['Completely denoralized', 'Partially denoralized', 'Completely normalized', 'Party normalized'],
                'answer': 'Completely normalized'
            }


        ]
    },


]
sem_7 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'GRID AND CLOUD COMPUTING LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The term ‘Cloud’ in cloud-computing refers to ______.',
                        'options': ['The Internet', 'Cumulus Clouds', 'A Computer', 'Thin Clients'],
                        'answer': 'The Internet'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What type of computing technology refers to services and applications that typically run on a distributed network through virtualized resources?',
                'options': ['Distributed Computing', 'Cloud Computing', 'Soft Computing', 'Parallel Computing'],
                'answer': 'Cloud Computing'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A hybrid cloud is built with ________ and ___________ clouds.',
                'options': ['community, private', 'community, public', 'hybrid, community', 'public, private'],
                'answer': 'D)public, private'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Virtual Machine Ware (VMware) is an example of___________.',
                'options': ['Infrastructure Service', 'Platform Service', 'Software Service', 'Hardware Service'],
                'answer': 'Infrastructure Service'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The PaaS model enables the user to deploy applications onto a virtualized______________.',
                'options': ['grid platform', 'hypervisor', 'cloud platform', 'grid and cloud'],
                'answer': 'cloud platform'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The virtualization layer known as ________________.',
                'options': ['VM', 'VMM', 'Both', 'None'],
                'answer': 'VM'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Threats to hypervisor and Virtual Servers are the ________ attacks.',
                'options': ['Host level', 'Application level', 'OS level', 'Network level'],
                'answer': 'Host level'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following has many features of that is now known as cloud computing?',
                'options': ['Web Service', 'Software', 'All of the mentioned', 'Internet'],
                'answer': 'Internet'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The software that supports virtual machine is called?',
                'options': ['VMM', 'Hypervisor', 'Kernel', 'Both A and B'],
                'answer': 'Both A and B'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Hypervisor or VMM can directly communicate with the hardware is known as?',
                'options': ['Bare metal hypervisor', 'Hosted Hypervisor', 'Virtual monitor machine', 'Both A and B'],
                'answer': 'Bare metal hypervisor'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Specifies the layout of android screen use_____file.',
                        'options': ['R', 'manifest', 'layout', 'None of these'],
                        'answer': 'layout'
            },
            {
                'question': '______ contains the R.java file.',
                'options': ['src', 'gen', 'Both A and B', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'gen'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In memory, Activity doesn’t exist That is____state.',
                'options': ['initial', 'running', 'starting', 'All of these'],
                'answer': 'starting'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Src folder contain____files',
                'options': ['Java source code', 'XML', 'manifest', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Java source code'
            },

            {
                'question': 'which class store additional information?',
                'options': ['Bundle', 'Data store', 'Extra', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Bundle'
            },
            {
                'question': '_____method is used to close an activity',
                'options': ['Finish', 'Stop', 'Close', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Finish'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which is not an Android component of the following?',
                'options': ['Layout', 'Service', ' Activity', 'Content Provider'],
                'answer': 'Service'
            },
            {
                'question': ' ______ is the name of the class used by Intent to store additional information?',
                'options': ['Parcelable', 'Extra', 'Bundle', 'DataStore'],
                'answer': 'Bundle'
            },

            {
                'question': '_______is not included in the Android application framework?',
                'options': ['Notification Manager', 'Window Manager', 'Dialer Manager', 'Package Manager'],
                'answer': 'Dialer Manager'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which is a Java call-back method invoked when a view is clicked of the following?',
                'options': ['Detector', 'OnTapListener', 'OnClickDetector', 'OnClickListener'],
                'answer': 'OnClickListener'
            }



        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT LAB',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Specifies the layout of android screen use_____file.',
                        'options': ['R', 'manifest', 'layout', 'None of these'],
                        'answer': 'layout'
            },
            {
                'question': '______ contains the R.java file.',
                'options': ['src', 'gen', 'Both A and B', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'gen'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In memory, Activity doesn’t exist That is____state.',
                'options': ['initial', 'running', 'starting', 'All of these'],
                'answer': 'starting'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Src folder contain____files',
                'options': ['Java source code', 'XML', 'manifest', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Java source code'
            },

            {
                'question': 'which class store additional information?',
                'options': ['Bundle', 'Data store', 'Extra', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Bundle'
            },
            {
                'question': '_____method is used to close an activity',
                'options': ['Finish', 'Stop', 'Close', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Finish'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which is not an Android component of the following?',
                'options': ['Layout', 'Service', ' Activity', 'Content Provider'],
                'answer': 'Service'
            },
            {
                'question': ' ______ is the name of the class used by Intent to store additional information?',
                'options': ['Parcelable', 'Extra', 'Bundle', 'DataStore'],
                'answer': 'Bundle'
            },

            {
                'question': '_______is not included in the Android application framework?',
                'options': ['Notification Manager', 'Window Manager', 'Dialer Manager', 'Package Manager'],
                'answer': 'Dialer Manager'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which is a Java call-back method invoked when a view is clicked of the following?',
                'options': ['Detector', 'OnTapListener', 'OnClickDetector', 'OnClickListener'],
                'answer': 'OnClickListener'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'SOFTWARE PROJECT MANAGEMENT',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not project management goal?',
                'options': ['Keeping overall costs within budget', 'Delivering the software to the customer at the agreed time', 'Maintaining a happy and well-functioning development team', 'Avoiding customer complaints'],
                'answer': 'Avoiding customer complaints'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not considered as a risk in project management?',
                'options': ['Specification delays', 'Product competition', 'Testing', 'Staff turnover'],
                'answer': 'Testing'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The process each manager follows during the life of a project is known as',
                'options': ['Project Management', 'Manager life cycle', 'Project Management Life Cycle', 'All of the mentioned'],
                'answer': 'Project Management Life Cycle'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A 66.6% risk is considered as',
                'options': ['very low', 'low', 'moderate', 'high'],
                'answer': 'high'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Quality planning is the process of developing a quality plan for',
                'options': ['team', 'project', 'customers', 'project manager'],
                'answer': 'project'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is incorrect activity for the configuration management of a software system?',
                'options': ['Internship management', 'Change management', 'Version management', 'System management'],
                'answer': 'Internship management'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Identify the sub-process of process improvement',
                'options': ['Process introduction', 'Process analysis', 'De-processification', 'Process distribution'],
                'answer': 'Process analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What limits the options of the project team?',
                'options': ['Constraints', 'Assumptions', 'Technology', 'Deliverables'],
                'answer': 'Constraints'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The work breakdown that covers the acquisition of a specific defense material item and is related to contractual effort, is called______',
                'options': ['Contract WBS', 'Contract Program WBS', 'Program WBS', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Program WBS'
            },
            {
                'question': 'How many Work Breakdown Structure are there',
                'options': ['Three', 'Two', 'Four', 'None of these'],
                'answer': 'Two'
            },

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'INFORMATION SECURITY',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': '____________ is an action to breach the security policies?',
                        'options': ['Security Attack', 'Security Mechanism', 'Security Service', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'Security Attack'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is used to enhance the security?',
                'options': ['Security Attack', 'Security Mechanism', 'Security Service', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'Security Service'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is an symmetric encryption algorithm? ',
                'options': ['DES', 'AES', 'RC4', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'

            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a stream cipher?',
                'options': ['RC4', 'DES', 'AES', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'RC4'

            },

            {
                'question': 'CIA stands for?',
                'options': ['Connection, Integrity, Assurance', 'Confidentiality, Identity, Availability', 'Connection, Integrity, Availability', 'Confidentiality, Integrity, Availability'],
                'answer': 'Connection, Integrity, Availability'

            },
            {
                'question': 'DES stands for?',
                'options': ['Dynamic Encryption Standard', 'Data Electronics Standard', 'Digital Electronics Standard', 'Data Encryption Standard'],
                'answer': 'Data Encryption Standard'
            },
            {
                'question': 'AES stands for?',
                'options': ['Automatic Encryption Standard', 'Automatic Electronics Standard', 'Advanced Encryption Standard', 'Advanced Electronics Standard'],
                'answer': 'Advanced Encryption Standard'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a substitution technique?',
                'options': ['Hill cipher', 'One time pad', 'Play fair', 'rail fence'],
                'answer': 'Rail fence'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the plain text block size of DES?',
                'options': ['32 bits', '128 bits', '64 bits', '256 bits'],
                'answer': '64 bits'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What is the plain text block size of AES?',
                'options': ['256 bits', '1024 bits', '64 bits', '64 bits'],
                'answer': '64 bits'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'GRID AND CLOUD COMPUTING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'The term ‘Cloud’ in cloud-computing refers to ______.',
                        'options': ['The Internet', 'Cumulus Clouds', 'A Computer', 'Thin Clients'],
                        'answer': 'The Internet'
            },
            {
                'question': 'What type of computing technology refers to services and applications that typically run on a distributed network through virtualized resources?',
                'options': ['Distributed Computing', 'Cloud Computing', 'Soft Computing', 'Parallel Computing'],
                'answer': 'Cloud Computing'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A hybrid cloud is built with ________ and ___________ clouds.',
                'options': ['community, private', 'community, public', 'hybrid, community', 'public, private'],
                'answer': 'D)public, private'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Virtual Machine Ware (VMware) is an example of___________.',
                'options': ['Infrastructure Service', 'Platform Service', 'Software Service', 'Hardware Service'],
                'answer': 'Infrastructure Service'
            },

            {
                'question': 'The PaaS model enables the user to deploy applications onto a virtualized______________.',
                'options': ['grid platform', 'hypervisor', 'cloud platform', 'grid and cloud'],
                'answer': 'cloud platform'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The virtualization layer known as ________________.',
                'options': ['VM', 'VMM', 'Both', 'None'],
                'answer': 'VM'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Threats to hypervisor and Virtual Servers are the ________ attacks.',
                'options': ['Host level', 'Application level', 'OS level', 'Network level'],
                'answer': 'Host level'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following has many features of that is now known as cloud computing?',
                'options': ['Web Service', 'Software', 'All of the mentioned', 'Internet'],
                'answer': 'Internet'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The software that supports virtual machine is called?',
                'options': ['VMM', 'Hypervisor', 'Kernel', 'Both A and B'],
                'answer': 'Both A and B'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Hypervisor or VMM can directly communicate with the hardware is known as?',
                'options': ['Bare metal hypervisor', 'Hosted Hypervisor', 'Virtual monitor machine', 'Both A and B'],
                'answer': 'Bare metal hypervisor'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MACHINE LEARNING',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'ML is a field of AI consisting of learning algorithms that?',
                        'options': ['Improve their performance', 'At executing some task', 'Over time with experience', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'High entropy means that the partitions in classification are',
                'options': ['pure', 'not pure', 'useful', 'useless'],
                'answer': 'not pure'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a widely used and effective machine learning algorithm based on the idea of bagging?',
                'options': ['Decision Tree', 'Random Forest', 'Regression', 'Classification'],
                'answer': 'Random Forest'
            },
            {
                'question': ' Different learning methods do not include?',
                'options': ['Memorization', 'Analogy', 'Introduction', 'Deduction'],
                'answer': 'Introduction'
            },

            {
                'question': 'When performing regression or classification, which of the following is the correct way to preprocess the data?',
                'options': ['Normalize the data → PCA → training', 'PCA → normalize PCA output → training', 'Normalize the data → PCA → normalize PCA output → training', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Normalize the data → PCA → training'
            },
            {
                'question': 'How do you handle missing or corrupted data in a dataset?',
                'options': ['Drop missing rows or columns', 'Replace missing values with mean/median/mode', 'Assign a unique category to missing values', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The most widely used metrics and tools to assess a classification model are:',
                'options': ['Confusion matrix', 'Cost-sensitive accuracy', 'Area under the ROC curve', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'A model of language consists of the categories which do not include?',
                'options': ['Language units', 'Structural units', 'Role structure of units', 'System constraints'],
                'answer': 'Structural units'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Suppose we would like to perform clustering on spatial data such as the geometrical locations of houses. We wish to produce clusters of many different sizes and shapes. Which of the following methods is the most appropriate?',
                'options': ['Decision Trees', 'Model-based clustering', 'K-means clustering', 'Density-based clustering'],
                'answer': 'Density-based clustering'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is a disadvantage of decision trees?',
                'options': ['Factor analysis', 'Decision trees are robust to outliers', 'Decision trees are prone to be overfit', 'None of the above'],
                'answer': 'Decision trees are prone to be overfit'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'MANAGEMENT SCIENCE',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': '_______________ is a function of Management.',
                        'options': ['Planning', 'Organizing', 'Staffing', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Theory of hierarchy of human relations and discipline based on their needs is formulated by _________________',
                'options': ['Elton Mayo', 'Maslow', 'Douglas McGregor', 'Herzberg'],
                'answer': 'Maslow'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The type of leadership style where leader commands the followers and expects compliance from them is called _________________',
                'options': ['Autocratic Leadership Style', 'Democratic Leadership Style', 'Free Reign Leadership Style', 'Monopoly Leadership Style'],
                'answer': 'Autocratic Leadership Style'
            },
            {
                'question': 'According to Herzberg;s Two factor theory, "Job Content" is a _______________',
                'options': ['Motivational Factor', 'Dissatisfier', 'Satisfier', 'Both A&C'],
                'answer': 'Both A&C'
            },

            {
                'question': '_________________ is the physical arrangement of equipment and facilities within a plant',
                'options': ['Plant Design', 'Plant Plan', 'Plant Layout', 'Plant Outlook'],
                'answer': 'Plant Layout'
            },
            {
                'question': '_______________ is a type of plant layout',
                'options': ['Process layout', 'Product layout', 'Combined layout', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'With __________________ a single worker/ group of workers handle the complete task',
                'options': ['Job production', 'Batch Production', 'Mass Production', 'None'],
                'answer': 'Job production'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Indentify the component of Work measurement',
                'options': ['Reporting', 'Preferred Methods', 'Time Values', 'All the above'],
                'answer': 'All the above'
            },
            {
                'question': '________________ is a procedure intended to ensure that a manufactured product adheres to a defined set of quality criteria',
                'options': ['Quantity Control', 'Statistical Control', 'Quality Control', 'Management Control'],
                'answer': 'Quality Control'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The Deming quality cycle is ____________',
                'options': ['PLAN DO ACT CHECK', 'PLAN ACT DO CHECK', 'DO CHECK PLAN ACT', 'PLAN DO CHECK ACT'],
                'answer': 'PLAN DO CHECK ACT'
            }

        ]
    },
]
sem_8 = [
    {
        'subject_name': 'CYBER SECURITY',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Which of the following is considered as the unsolicited commercial email?',
                        'options': ['Virus', 'Malware', 'Spam', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'Spam'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following usually observe each activity on the internet of the victim, gather all information in the background, and send it to someone else?',
                'options': ['Malware', 'Spyware', 'Adware', 'All of the Above'],
                'answer': 'Spyware'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which one of the following is a type of antivirus program?',
                'options': ['Quick heal', 'Mcafee', 'Kaspersky', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following refers to the violation of the principle if a computer is no more accessible?',
                'options': ['Access control', 'Confidentiality', 'Availability', 'All of the above'],
                'answer': 'Availability'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Which of the following port and IP address scanner famous among the users?',
                'options': ['Cain and Abel', 'Angry IP Scanner', 'Snort', 'Ettercap'],
                'answer': 'Angry IP Scanner'
            },
            {
                'question': '_________ framework made cracking of vulnerabilities easy like point and click.',
                'options': ['.Net', 'Metasploit', 'Zeus', 'Ettercap'],
                'answer': 'Metasploit'
            },
            {
                'question': '__________ is a popular tool used for discovering networks as well as in security auditing.',
                'options': ['Ettercap', 'Metasploit', 'Nmap', 'Burp Suit'],
                'answer': 'Nmap'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the below-mentioned tool is used for Wi-Fi hacking?',
                'options': ['Wireshark', 'Nessus', 'Aircrack-ng', 'Snort'],
                'answer': 'Aircrack-ng'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Wireshark is a ____________ tool',
                'options': ['network protocol analysis', 'network connection security', 'connection analysis', 'defending malicious packet-filtering'],
                'answer': 'network protocol analysis'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following deals with network intrusion detection and real-time traffic analysis?',
                'options': ['John the Ripper', 'L0phtCrack', 'Snort', 'Nessus'],
                'answer': 'Snort'
            }

        ]
    },
    {
        'subject_name': 'DATA ANALYTICS',
        'QUESTIONS': [
            {
                        'question': 'Data Analysis is a process of?',
                        'options': ['Inspecting data', 'Cleaning data', 'Transforming data', 'All of the above'],
                        'answer': 'All of the above'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is not a major data analysis approach?',
                'options': ['Data Mining', 'Predictive Intelligence', 'Business Intelligence', 'Text Analytics'],
                'answer': 'Predictive Intelligence'
            },
            {
                'question': 'How many main statistical methodologies are used in data analysis',
                'options': ['2', '3', '4', '5'],
                'answer': '2'
            },
            {
                'question': 'In descriptive statistics, data from the entire population or a sample is summarized with ?',
                'options': ['Integer descriptors', 'Floating descriptors ', 'Numerical descriptors', 'Decimal descriptors'],
                'answer': 'Numerical descriptors'
            },

            {
                'question': 'Data Analysis is defined by the statistician?',
                'options': ['William S.', 'Hans Peter Luhn', 'Gregory Piatetsky-Shapiro', 'John Tukey'],
                'answer': 'John Tukey'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is true about hypothesis testing?',
                'options': ['answering yes/no questions about the data', 'estimating numerical characteristics of the data', 'describing associations within the data', 'modeling relationships within the data'],
                'answer': 'answering yes/no questions about the data'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The branch of statistics which deals with development of particular statistical methods is classified as',
                'options': ['industry statistics', 'economic statistics', 'applied mathematics', 'applied statistics'],
                'answer': 'applied statistics'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Which of the following is true about regression analysis?',
                'options': ['answering yes/no questions about the data', 'estimating numerical characteristics of the data', 'modeling relationships within the data', 'describing associations within the data'],
                'answer': 'modeling relationships within the data'
            },
            {
                'question': 'Text Analytics, also referred to as Text Mining?',
                'options': ['TRUE', 'FALSE', 'Can be true or false', 'Can not say'],
                'answer': 'TRUE'
            },
            {
                'question': 'The goal of business intelligence is to allow easy interpretation of large volumes of data to identify new opportunities.',
                'options': ['TRUE', 'FALSE', 'Can be true or false', 'Can not say'],
                'answer': 'TRUE'
            },

        ]
    },

]
